PAMPHLET O
8 O
Richard B-Person
Bland I-Person
, O
An O
Inquiry O
into O
the O
Rights O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Colonies I-Organization
, O
Intended O
as O
an O
Answer O
to O
the O
Regulations O
Lately O
Made O
Concerning O
the O
Colonies B-Location
, O
and O
the O
Taxes O
Imposed O
upon O
Them O
Considered O
. O

In O
a O
Letter O
Addressed O
to O
the O
Author B-Person
of I-Person
That I-Person
Pamphlet I-Person
. O

Williamsburg B-Location
, O
1766 O
. O

Many O
Americans O
were O
not O
willing O
to O
concede O
as O
much O
as O
Daniel B-Person
Dulany I-Person
to O
the O
idea O
of O
virtual O
representation O
; O
instead O
they O
conceived O
of O
an O
alternative O
— O
“ O
actual O
representation O
” O
they O
called O
it—more O
in O
accord O
with O
their O
own O
experience O
. O

The O
origins O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
’ O
s O
crazy O
quilt O
pattern O
of O
representation O
may O
have O
been O
lost O
in O
the O
mists O
of O
time O
, O
but O
this O
was O
not O
true O
of O
the O
colonists O
. O

When O
new O
counties O
were O
created O
in O
Virginia B-Location
or O
new O
towns O
in O
Massachusetts B-Location
, O
they O
had O
sent O
delegates O
to O
their O
respective O
assemblies B-Organization
. O

Most O
colonists O
instinctively O
believed O
, O
as O
one O
Pennsylvanian O
put O
it O
, O
that O
the O
people O
“ O
should O
be O
consulted O
in O
the O
most O
particular O
manner O
that O
can O
be O
imagined O
. O
” O

Indeed O
, O
election O
for O
most O
Americans O
had O
become O
the O
sole O
criterion O
of O
representation O
, O
not O
just O
for O
themselves O
, O
but O
for O
everyone O
. O

“ O
To O
what O
purpose O
, O
” O
asked O
James B-Person
Otis I-Person
, O
“ O
is O
it O
to O
ring O
everlasting O
changes O
to O
the O
colonists O
on O
the O
cases O
of O
Manchester B-Location
, O
Birmingham B-Organization
and O
Sheffield B-Location
, O
who O
return O
no O
members O
? O

If O
those O
now O
so O
considerable O
places O
are O
not O
represented O
, O
they O
ought O
to O
be O
. O
” O

Richard B-Person
Bland I-Person
was O
one O
of O
the O
more O
important O
planter-aristocrats O
of O
Virginia B-Location
and O
a O
long-time O
and O
hard-working O
member O
of O
the O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Burgesses I-Organization
. O

In O
the O
following O
pamphlet O
he O
confronted O
Whately B-Person
’ O
s O
argument O
directly O
and O
followed O
the O
path O
that O
Dulany B-Person
had O
opened O
in O
seeking O
to O
clarify O
the O
line O
that O
presumably O
existed O
between O
the O
authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
and O
the O
rights O
of O
the O
colonists O
. O

Since O
the O
English O
constitution O
and O
ancient O
history O
offered O
no O
help O
“ O
in O
fixing O
the O
proper O
Connexion O
between O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
and O
the O
Mother B-Organization
Kingdom I-Organization
; O
. O
. O
. O
we O
must O
, O
” O
said O
Bland O
, O
“ O
have O
Recourse O
to O
the O
Law O
of O
Nature O
, O
and O
those O
Rights O
of O
Mankind O
which O
flow O
from O
it O
. O
” O

And O
because O
“ O
Rights O
imply O
Equality O
, O
” O
the O
colonists O
ought O
to O
be O
treated O
equally O
in O
the O
empire B-Location
. O

Perhaps O
the O
Americans O
were O
, O
as O
English B-Organization
officials I-Organization
sometimes O
implied O
, O
“ O
a O
distinct O
People O
. O
” O

In O
the O
end O
, O
however O
, O
Bland O
drew O
back O
from O
the O
radical O
implications O
of O
his O
appeal O
to O
nature O
. O

Reflecting O
on O
Bland O
’ O
s O
pamphlet O
in O
an O
1815 O
letter O
, O
Thomas B-Person
Jefferson I-Person
identified O
a O
curious O
tension O
in O
its O
argument O
, O
one O
symbolic O
of O
the O
fitful O
approach O
of O
many O
American O
writers O
in O
the O
debate O
: O
“ O
He O
would O
set O
out O
with O
a O
set O
of O
sound O
principles O
, O
pursue O
them O
logically O
till O
he O
found O
them O
leading O
to O
the O
precipice O
which O
he O
had O
to O
leap O
, O
start O
back O
alarmed O
, O
then O
resume O
his O
ground O
, O
go O
over O
it O
in O
another O
direction O
, O
be O
led O
by O
the O
correctness O
of O
his O
reasoning O
to O
the O
same O
place O
and O
again O
back O
about O
and O
try O
other O
processes O
to O
reconcile O
right O
and O
wrong O
but O
finally O
left O
his O
reader O
and O
himself O
bewildered O
between O
the O
steady O
index O
of O
the O
compass O
in O
their O
hand O
, O
and O
the O
phantasm O
to O
which O
it O
seemed O
to O
point O
. O
” O

An O
Inquiry O
into O
the O
Rights O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Colonies I-Organization
. O

I O
SIR O
, O
the O
Liberty O
to O
address O
you O
, O
as O
the O
Author B-Person
of I-Person
“ I-Person
The I-Person
Regulations I-Person
lately I-Person
made I-Person
concerning I-Person
the I-Person
Colonies I-Person
, I-Person
and I-Person
the I-Person
Taxes I-Person
imposed I-Person
upon I-Person
them I-Person
TAKE I-Person
considered I-Person
. I-Person
” I-Person

It O
is O
not O
to O
the O
Man O
, O
whoever O
you O
are O
, O
that O
I O
address O
myself O
; O
but O
it O
is O
to O
the O
Author B-Person
of O
a O
Pamphlet O
which O
, O
according O
to O
the O
Light O
I O
view O
it O
in O
, O
endeavours O
to O
fix O
Shackles O
upon O
the O
American B-Organization
Colonies I-Organization
: O
Shackles O
which O
, O
however O
nicely O
polished O
, O
can O
by O
no O
Means O
sit O
easy O
upon O
Men O
who O
have O
just O
Sentiments O
of O
their O
own O
Rights O
and O
Liberties O
. O

You O
have O
indeed O
brought O
this O
Trouble O
upon O
yourself O
, O
for O
you O
say O
that O
“ O
many O
Steps O
have O
been O
lately O
taken O
by O
the O
Ministry B-Organization
to O
cement O
and O
perfect O
the O
necessary O
Connexion O
between O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
and O
the O
Mother B-Organization
Kingdom I-Organization
, O
which O
every O
Man O
who O
is O
sincerely O
interested O
in O
what O
is O
interesting O
to O
his O
Country B-Organization
will O
anxiously O
consider O
the O
Propriety O
of O
, O
will O
inquire O
into O
the O
Information O
, O
and O
canvas O
the O
Principles O
upon O
which O
they O
have O
been O
adopted O
; O
and O
will O
be O
ready O
to O
applaud O
what O
has O
been O
well O
done O
, O
condemn O
what O
has O
been O
done O
amiss O
, O
and O
suggest O
any O
Emendations O
, O
Improvements O
, O
or O
Additions O
, O
which O
may O
be O
within O
his O
Knowledge O
, O
and O
occur O
to O
his O
Reflexion O
. O
” O

Encouraged O
therefore O
by O
so O
candid O
an O
Invitation O
, O
I O
have O
undertaken O
to O
examine O
, O
with O
an O
honest O
Plainness O
and O
Freedom O
, O
whether O
the O
Ministry B-Organization
, O
by O
imposing O
Taxes O
upon O
the O
Colonies B-Location
by O
Authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
have O
pursued O
a O
wise O
and O
salutary O
Plan O
of O
Government O
, O
or O
whether O
they O
have O
exerted O
pernicious O
and O
destructive O
Acts O
of O
Power O
. O

I O
pretend O
not O
to O
concern O
myself O
with O
the O
Regulations O
lately O
made O
to O
encourage O
Population O
in O
the O
new O
Acquisitions O
: O
Time O
can O
only O
determine O
whether O
the O
Reasons O
upon O
which O
they O
have O
been O
founded O
are O
agreeable O
to O
the O
Maxims O
of O
Trade O
and O
sound O
Policy O
, O
or O
not O
. O

However O
, O
I O
will O
venture O
to O
observe O
that O
if O
the O
most O
powerful O
Inducement O
towards O
peopling O
those O
Acquisitions O
is O
to O
arise O
from O
the O
Expectation O
of O
a O
Constitution O
to O
be O
established O
in O
them O
similar O
to O
the O
other O
Royal B-Organization
Governments I-Organization
in I-Organization
America I-Organization
, O
it O
must O
be O
a O
strong O
Circumstance O
, O
in O
my O
Opinion O
, O
against O
their O
being O
settled O
by O
Englishmen O
, O
or O
even O
by O
Foreigners O
, O
who O
do O
not O
live O
under O
the O
most O
despotick O
Government O
; O
since O
, O
upon O
your O
Principles O
of O
Colony O
Government O
, O
such O
a O
Constitution O
will O
not O
be O
worth O
their O
Acceptance O
. O

The O
Question O
is O
whether O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
represented O
in O
the O
British B-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
or O
not O
? O

You O
affirm O
it O
to O
be O
an O
indubitable O
Fact O
that O
they O
are O
represented O
, O
and O
from O
thence O
you O
infer O
a O
Right O
in O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
to O
impose O
Taxes O
of O
every O
Kind O
upon O
them O
. O

You O
do O
not O
insist O
upon O
the O
Power O
, O
but O
upon O
the O
Right O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
to O
impose O
Taxes O
upon O
the O
Colonies B-Location
. O

This O
is O
certainly O
a O
very O
proper O
Distinction O
, O
as O
Right O
and O
Power O
have O
very O
different O
Meanings O
, O
and O
convey O
very O
different O
Ideas O
: O
For O
had O
you O
told O
us O
that O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great I-Organization
Britain I-Organization
have O
Power O
, O
by O
the O
Fleets O
and O
Armies O
of O
the O
Kingdom B-Location
, O
to O
impose O
Taxes O
and O
to O
raise O
Contributions O
upon O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
I O
should O
not O
have O
presumed O
to O
dispute O
the O
Point O
with O
you O
; O
but O
as O
you O
insist O
upon O
the O
Right O
only O
, O
I O
must O
beg O
Leave O
to O
differ O
from O
you O
in O
Opinion O
, O
and O
shall O
give O
my O
Reasons O
for O
it O
. O

But O
I O
must O
first O
recapitulate O
your O
Arguments O
in O
Support O
of O
this O
Right O
in O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
. O

You O
say O
“ O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
do O
not O
indeed O
choose O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
neither O
are O
nine O
Tenths O
of O
the O
People O
of O
Britain O
Electors O
; O
for O
the O
Right O
of O
Election O
is O
annexed O
to O
certain O
Species O
of O
Property O
, O
to O
peculiar O
Franchises O
, O
and O
to O
Inhabitancy O
in O
some O
particular O
Places O
. O

But O
these O
Descriptions O
comprehend O
only O
a O
very O
small O
Part O
of O
the O
Lands O
, O
the O
Property O
and O
People O
of O
Britain B-Location
; O
all O
Copy-Hold O
, O
all O
Lease-Hold O
Estates O
under O
the O
Crown B-Organization
, O
under O
the O
Church B-Organization
, O
or O
under O
private O
Persons O
, O
though O
for O
Terms O
ever O
so O
long O
; O
all O
landed O
Property O
in O
short O
that O
is O
not O
Freehold O
, O
and O
all O
monied O
Property O
whatsoever O
, O
are O
excluded O
. O

The O
Possessors O
of O
these O
have O
no O
Votes O
in O
the O
Election O
of O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
; O
Women O
and O
Persons O
under O
Age O
, O
be O
their O
Property O
ever O
so O
large O
, O
and O
all O
of O
it O
Freehold O
, O
have O
none O
: O
The O
Merchants O
of O
London B-Location
, O
a O
numerous O
and O
respectable O
Body O
of O
Men O
, O
whose O
Opulence O
exceeds O
all O
that O
America B-Organization
can O
collect O
; O
the O
Proprietors O
of O
that O
vast O
Accumulation O
of O
Wealth O
, O
the O
Publick O
Funds O
; O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
Leeds B-Location
, O
of O
Halifax B-Location
, O
of O
Birmingham B-Location
, O
and O
of O
Manchester B-Location
, O
Towns O
that O
are O
each O
of O
them O
larger O
than O
the O
largest O
in O
the O
Plantations B-Location
; O
many O
of O
lesser O
Note O
, O
that O
are O
incorporated O
; O
and O
that O
great O
Corporation O
the O
East B-Organization
India I-Organization
Company I-Organization
, O
whose O
Rights O
over O
the O
Countries O
they O
possess O
fall O
very O
little O
short O
of O
Sovereignty O
, O
and O
whose O
Trade O
and O
whose O
Fleets O
are O
sufficient O
to O
constitute O
them O
a O
maritime O
Power O
, O
are O
all O
in O
the O
same O
Circumstances O
: O
And O
yet O
are O
they O
not O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
? O

Is O
their O
vast O
Property O
subject O
to O
Taxation O
without O
their O
Consent O
? O

Are O
they O
all O
arbitrarily O
bound O
by O
Laws O
to O
which O
they O
have O
not O
agreed O
? O

The O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
exactly O
in O
the O
same O
Situation O
; O
all O
British O
Subjects O
are O
really O
in O
the O
same O
; O
none O
are O
actually O
, O
all O
are O
virtually O
, O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
: O
For O
every O
Member O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
sits O
in O
the O
House B-Organization
not O
as O
a O
Representative O
of O
his O
own O
Constituents O
, O
but O
as O
one O
of O
that O
august O
Assembly B-Organization
by O
which O
all O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great I-Organization
Britain I-Organization
are O
represented O
. O
” O

This O
is O
the O
Sum O
of O
what O
you O
advance O
, O
in O
all O
the O
Pomp O
of O
Parliamentary O
Declamation O
, O
to O
prove O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
and O
therefore O
subject O
to O
their O
Taxation O
; O
but O
notwithstanding O
this O
Way O
of O
reasoning O
, O
I O
cannot O
comprehend O
how O
Men O
who O
are O
excluded O
from O
voting O
at O
the O
Election O
of O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
can O
be O
represented O
in O
that O
Assembly B-Organization
, O
or O
how O
those O
who O
are O
elected O
do O
not O
sit O
in O
the O
House B-Organization
as O
Representatives O
of O
their O
Constituents O
. O

These O
Assertions O
appear O
to O
me O
not O
only O
paradoxical O
, O
but O
contrary O
to O
the O
fundamental O
Principles O
of O
the O
English O
Constitution O
. O

To O
illustrate O
this O
important O
Disquisition O
, O
I O
conceive O
we O
must O
recur O
to O
the O
civil O
Constitution O
of O
England B-Organization
, O
and O
from O
thence O
deduce O
and O
ascertain O
the O
Rights O
and O
Privileges O
of O
the O
People O
at O
the O
first O
Establishment O
of O
the O
Government B-Organization
, O
and O
discover O
the O
Alterations O
that O
have O
been O
made O
in O
them O
from O
Time O
to O
Time O
; O
and O
it O
is O
from O
the O
Laws O
of O
the O
Kingdom B-Organization
, O
founded O
upon O
the O
Principles O
of O
the O
Law O
of O
Nature O
, O
that O
we O
are O
to O
show O
the O
Obligation O
every O
Member O
of O
the O
State B-Organization
is O
under O
to O
pay O
Obedience O
to O
its O
Institutions O
. O

From O
these O
Principles O
I O
shall O
endeavour O
to O
prove O
that O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
Britain B-Location
, O
who O
have O
no O
Vote O
in O
the O
Election O
of O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
are O
not O
represented O
in O
that O
Assembly B-Organization
, O
and O
yet O
that O
they O
owe O
Obedience O
to O
the O
Laws O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
; O
which O
, O
as O
to O
them O
, O
are O
constitutional O
, O
and O
not O
arbitrary O
. O

As O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
I O
shall O
consider O
them O
afterwards O
. O

Now O
it O
is O
a O
Fact O
, O
as O
certain O
as O
History O
can O
make O
it O
, O
that O
the O
present O
civil O
Constitution O
of O
England B-Organization
derives O
its O
Original O
from O
those O
Saxons O
who O
, O
coming O
over O
to O
the O
Assistance O
of O
the O
Britons O
in O
the O
Time O
of O
their O
King B-Person
Vortigern I-Person
, O
made O
themselves O
Masters O
of O
the O
Kingdom B-Location
, O
and O
established O
a O
Form O
of O
Government O
in O
it O
similar O
to O
that O
they O
had O
been O
accustomed O
to O
live O
under O
in O
their O
native O
Country B-Location
; O
1 O
as O
similar O
, O
at O
least O
, O
as O
the O
Difference O
of O
their O
Situation O
and O
Circumstances O
would O
permit O
. O

This O
Government B-Organization
, O
like O
that O
from O
whence O
they O
came O
, O
was O
founded O
upon O
Principles O
of O
the O
most O
perfect O
Liberty O
: O
The O
conquered O
Lands O
were O
divided O
among O
the O
Individuals O
in O
Proportion O
to O
the O
Rank O
they O
held O
in O
the O
Nation B-Organization
; O
2 O
and O
every O
Freeman O
, O
that O
is O
, O
every O
Freeholder O
, O
was O
a O
Member O
of O
their O
Wittinagemot B-Organization
, O
or O
Parliament B-Organization
.3 O
The O
other O
Part O
of O
the O
Nation B-Organization
, O
or O
the O
Non-Proprietors O
of O
Land O
, O
were O
of O
little O
Estimation O
.4 O
They O
, O
as O
in O
Germany B-Location
, O
were O
either O
Slaves O
, O
mere O
Hewers O
of O
Wood O
and O
Drawers O
of O
Water O
, O
or O
Freedmen O
; O
who O
, O
being O
of O
foreign O
Extraction O
, O
had O
been O
manumitted O
by O
their O
Masters O
, O
and O
were O
excluded O
from O
the O
high O
Privilege O
of O
having O
a O
Share O
in O
the O
Administration B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Commonwealth I-Organization
, O
unless O
they O
became O
Proprietors O
of O
Land O
( O
which O
they O
might O
obtain O
by O
Purchase O
or O
Donation O
) O
and O
in O
that O
Case O
they O
had O
a O
Right O
to O
sit O
with O
the O
Freemen O
, O
in O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
or O
sovereign B-Organization
Legislature I-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
State I-Organization
. O

How O
long O
this O
Right O
of O
being O
personally O
present O
in O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
continued O
, O
or O
when O
the O
Custom O
of O
sending O
Representatives O
to O
this O
great B-Organization
Council I-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Nation I-Organization
, O
was O
first O
introduced O
, O
cannot O
be O
determined O
with O
Precision O
; O
but O
let O
the O
Custom O
of O
Representation O
be O
introduced O
when O
it O
will O
, O
it O
is O
certain O
that O
every O
Freeman O
, O
or O
, O
which O
was O
the O
same O
Thing O
in O
the O
Eye O
of O
the O
Constitution O
, O
every O
Freeholder O
, O
5 O
had O
a O
Right O
to O
vote O
at O
the O
Election O
of O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
and O
therefore O
might O
be O
said O
, O
with O
great O
Propriety O
, O
to O
be O
present O
in O
that O
Assembly B-Organization
, O
either O
in O
his O
own O
Person O
or O
by O
Representation O
. O

This O
Right O
of O
Election O
in O
the O
Freeholders O
is O
evident O
from O
the O
Statute O
1st O
Hen O
. O
5 O
. O

Ch O
. O
1st O
, O
which O
limits O
the O
Right O
of O
Election O
to O
those O
Freeholders O
only O
who O
are O
resident O
in O
the O
Counties O
the O
Day O
of O
the O
Date O
of O
the O
Writ O
of O
Election O
; O
but O
yet O
every O
resident O
Freeholder O
indiscriminately O
, O
let O
his O
Freehold O
be O
ever O
so O
small O
, O
had O
a O
Right O
to O
vote O
at O
the O
Election O
of O
Knights O
for O
his O
County O
, O
so O
that O
they O
were O
actually O
represented O
: O
And O
this O
Right O
of O
Election O
continued O
until O
it O
was O
taken O
away O
by O
the O
Statute O
8th O
Hen O
. O
6 O
. O

Ch O
. O
7 O
. O

from O
those O
Freeholders O
who O
had O
not O
a O
clear O
Freehold O
Estate O
of O
forty O
Shillings O
by O
the O
Year O
at O
the O
least O
. O

Now O
this O
Statute O
was O
deprivative O
of O
the O
Right O
of O
those O
Freeholders O
who O
came O
within O
the O
Description O
of O
it O
; O
but O
of O
what O
did O
it O
deprive O
them O
, O
if O
they O
were O
represented O
notwithstanding O
their O
Right O
of O
Election O
was O
taken O
from O
them O
? O

The O
mere O
Act O
of O
voting O
was O
nothing O
, O
of O
no O
Value O
, O
if O
they O
were O
represented O
as O
constitutionally O
without O
it O
as O
with O
it O
: O
But O
when O
by O
the O
fundamental O
Principles O
of O
the O
Constitution O
they O
were O
to O
be O
considered O
as O
Members O
of O
the O
Legislature B-Organization
, O
and O
as O
such O
had O
a O
Right O
to O
be O
present O
in O
Person O
, O
or O
to O
send O
their O
Procurators O
or O
Attornies O
, O
and O
by O
them O
to O
give O
their O
Suffrage O
in O
the O
supreme B-Organization
Council I-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Nation I-Organization
, O
this O
Statute O
deprived O
them O
of O
an O
essential O
Right O
; O
a O
Right O
without O
which O
, O
by O
the O
ancient O
Constitution O
of O
the O
State B-Organization
, O
all O
other O
Liberties O
were O
but O
a O
Species O
of O
Bondage O
. O

As O
these O
Freeholders O
then O
were O
deprived O
of O
their O
Rights O
to O
substitute O
Delegates O
to O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
they O
could O
not O
be O
represented O
, O
but O
were O
placed O
in O
the O
same O
Condition O
with O
the O
Non-Proprietors O
of O
Land O
, O
who O
were O
excluded O
by O
the O
original O
Constitution O
from O
having O
any O
Share O
in O
the O
Legislature B-Organization
, O
but O
who O
, O
notwithstanding O
such O
Exclusion O
, O
are O
bound O
to O
pay O
Obedience O
to O
the O
Laws O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
even O
if O
they O
should O
consist O
of O
nine O
Tenths O
of O
the O
People O
of O
Britain B-Location
; O
but O
then O
the O
Obligation O
of O
these O
Laws O
does O
not O
arise O
from O
their O
being O
virtually O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
but O
from O
a O
quite O
different O
Reason O
. O

Men O
in O
a O
State O
of O
Nature O
are O
absolutely O
free O
and O
independent O
of O
one O
another O
as O
to O
sovereign O
Jurisdiction O
, O
6 O
but O
when O
they O
enter O
into O
a O
Society O
, O
and O
by O
their O
own O
Consent O
become O
Members O
of O
it O
, O
they O
must O
submit O
to O
the O
Laws O
of O
the O
Society O
according O
to O
which O
they O
agree O
to O
be O
governed O
; O
for O
it O
is O
evident O
, O
by O
the O
very O
Act O
of O
Association O
, O
that O
each O
Member O
subjects O
himself O
to O
the O
Authority O
of O
that O
Body O
in O
whom O
, O
by O
common O
Consent O
, O
the O
legislative O
Power O
of O
the O
State O
is O
placed O
: O
But O
though O
they O
must O
submit O
to O
the O
Laws O
, O
so O
long O
as O
they O
remain O
Members O
of O
the O
Society O
, O
yet O
they O
retain O
so O
much O
of O
their O
natural O
Freedom O
as O
to O
have O
a O
Right O
to O
retire O
from O
the O
Society O
, O
to O
renounce O
the O
Benefits O
of O
it O
, O
to O
enter O
into O
another O
Society O
, O
and O
to O
settle O
in O
another O
Country O
; O
for O
their O
Engagements O
to O
the O
Society O
, O
and O
their O
Submission O
to O
the O
publick O
Authority O
of O
the O
State O
, O
do O
not O
oblige O
them O
to O
continue O
in O
it O
longer O
than O
they O
find O
it O
will O
conduce O
to O
their O
Happiness O
, O
which O
they O
have O
a O
natural O
Right O
to O
promote O
. O

This O
natural O
Right O
remains O
with O
every O
Man O
, O
and O
he O
cannot O
justly O
be O
deprived O
of O
it O
by O
any O
civil O
Authority O
. O

Every O
Person O
therefore O
who O
is O
denied O
his O
Share O
in O
the O
Legislature O
of O
the O
State B-Organization
to O
which O
he O
had O
an O
original O
Right O
, O
and O
every O
Person O
who O
from O
his O
particular O
Circumstances O
is O
excluded O
from O
this O
great O
Privilege O
, O
and O
refuses O
to O
exercise O
his O
natural O
Right O
of O
quitting O
the O
Country B-Organization
, O
but O
remains O
in O
it O
, O
and O
continues O
to O
exercise O
the O
Rights O
of O
a O
Citizen O
in O
all O
other O
Respects O
, O
must O
be O
subject O
to O
the O
Laws O
which O
by O
these O
Acts O
he O
implicitly O
, O
or O
to O
use O
your O
own O
Phrase O
, O
virtually O
consents O
to O
: O
For O
Men O
may O
subject O
themselves O
to O
Laws O
, O
by O
consenting O
to O
them O
implicitly O
; O
that O
is O
, O
by O
conforming O
to O
them O
, O
by O
adhering O
to O
the O
Society O
, O
and O
accepting O
the O
Benefits O
of O
its O
Constitution O
, O
as O
well O
, O
as O
explicitly O
and O
directly O
, O
in O
their O
own O
Persons O
, O
or O
by O
their O
Representatives O
substituted O
in O
their O
Room O
.7 O
Thus O
, O
if O
a O
Man O
whose O
Property O
does O
not O
entitle O
him O
to O
be O
an O
Elector O
of O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
and O
therefore O
cannot O
be O
represented O
, O
or O
have O
any O
Share O
in O
the O
Legislature O
, O
“ O
inherits O
or O
takes O
any O
Thing O
by O
the O
Laws O
of O
the O
Country B-Organization
to O
which O
he O
has O
no O
indubitable O
Right O
in O
Nature O
, O
or O
which O
, O
if O
he O
has O
a O
Right O
to O
it O
, O
he O
cannot O
tell O
how O
to O
get O
or O
keep O
without O
the O
Aid O
of O
the O
Laws O
and O
the O
Advantage O
of O
Society O
, O
then O
, O
when O
he O
takes O
this O
Inheritance O
, O
or O
whatever O
it O
is O
, O
with O
it O
he O
takes O
and O
owns O
the O
Laws O
that O
gave O
it O
him O
. O

And O
since O
the O
Security O
he O
has O
from O
the O
Laws O
of O
the O
Country B-Organization
, O
in O
Respect O
of O
his O
Person O
and O
Rights O
, O
is O
the O
Equivalent O
for O
his O
Submission O
to O
them O
, O
he O
cannot O
accept O
that O
Security O
without O
being O
obliged O
, O
in O
Equity O
, O
to O
pay O
this O
Submission O
: O
Nay O
his O
very O
continuing O
in O
the O
Country B-Organization
shows O
that O
he O
either O
likes O
the O
Constitution O
, O
or O
likes O
it O
better O
, O
notwithstanding O
the O
Alteration O
made O
in O
it O
to O
his O
Disadvantage O
, O
than O
any O
other O
; O
or O
at O
least O
thinks O
it O
better O
, O
in O
his O
Circumstances O
, O
to O
conform O
to O
it O
, O
than O
to O
seek O
any O
other O
; O
that O
is O
, O
he O
is O
content O
to O
be O
comprehended O
in O
it O
. O
” O

From O
hence O
it O
is O
evident O
that O
the O
Obligation O
of O
the O
Laws O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
upon O
the O
People O
of O
Britain B-Location
who O
have O
no O
Right O
to O
be O
Electors O
does O
not O
arise O
from O
their O
being O
virtually O
represented O
, O
but O
from O
a O
quite O
different O
Principle O
; O
a O
Principle O
of O
the O
Law O
of O
Nature O
, O
true O
, O
certain O
, O
and O
universal O
, O
applicable O
to O
every O
Sort O
of O
Government O
, O
and O
not O
contrary O
to O
the O
common O
Understandings O
of O
Mankind O
. O

If O
what O
you O
say O
is O
a O
real O
Fact O
, O
that O
nine O
Tenths O
of O
the O
People O
of O
Britain B-Location
are O
deprived O
of O
the O
high O
Privilege O
of O
being O
Electors O
, O
it O
shows O
a O
great O
Defect O
in O
the O
present O
Constitution O
, O
which O
has O
departed O
so O
much O
from O
its O
original O
Purity O
; O
but O
never O
can O
prove O
that O
those O
People O
are O
even O
virtually O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
. O

And O
here O
give O
me O
Leave O
to O
observe O
that O
it O
would O
be O
a O
Work O
worthy O
of O
the O
best O
patriotick O
Spirits O
in O
the O
Nation B-Location
to O
effectuate O
an O
Alteration O
in O
this O
putrid O
Part O
of O
the O
Constitution O
; O
and O
, O
by O
restoring O
it O
to O
its O
pristine O
Perfection O
, O
prevent O
any O
“ O
Order O
or O
Rank O
of O
the O
Subjects O
from O
imposing O
upon O
or O
binding O
the O
rest O
without O
their O
Consent O
. O
” O

But O
, O
I O
fear O
, O
the O
Gangrene O
has O
taken O
too O
deep O
Hold O
to O
be O
eradicated O
in O
these O
Days O
of O
Venality O
. O

But O
if O
those O
People O
of O
Britain B-Location
who O
are O
excluded O
from O
being O
Electors O
are O
not O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
the O
Conclusion O
is O
much O
stronger O
against O
the O
People O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
being O
represented O
; O
who O
are O
considered O
by O
the O
British B-Organization
Government I-Organization
itself O
, O
in O
every O
Instance O
of O
Parliamentary O
Legislation O
, O
as O
a O
distinct O
People O
. O

It O
has O
been O
determined O
by O
the O
Lords B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Privy I-Organization
Council I-Organization
that O
“ O
Acts O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
made O
in O
England B-Location
without O
naming O
the O
foreign O
Plantations B-Organization
will O
not O
bind O
them O
. O
” O
8 O
Now O
what O
can O
be O
the O
Reason O
of O
this O
Determination O
, O
but O
that O
the O
Lords B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Privy I-Organization
Council I-Organization
are O
of O
Opinion O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
a O
distinct O
People O
from O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
Britain B-Location
, O
and O
are O
not O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
. O

If O
, O
as O
you O
contend O
, O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
exactly O
in O
the O
same O
Situation O
with O
the O
Subjects O
in O
Britain B-Location
, O
the O
Laws O
will O
in O
every O
Instance O
be O
equally O
binding O
upon O
them O
, O
as O
upon O
those O
Subjects O
, O
unless O
you O
can O
discover O
two O
Species O
of O
virtual O
Representation O
; O
the O
one O
to O
respect O
the O
Subjects O
in O
Britain B-Location
, O
and O
always O
existing O
in O
Time O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
; O
the O
other O
to O
respect O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
a O
mere O
Non-Entity O
, O
if O
I O
may O
be O
allowed O
the O
Term O
, O
and O
never O
existing O
but O
when O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
thinks O
proper O
to O
produce O
it O
into O
Being O
by O
any O
particular O
Act O
in O
which O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
happen O
to O
be O
named O
. O

But O
I O
must O
examine O
the O
Case O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
more O
distinctly O
. O

It O
is O
in O
vain O
to O
search O
into O
the O
civil O
Constitution O
of O
England B-Organization
for O
Directions O
in O
fixing O
the O
proper O
Connexion O
between O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
and O
the O
Mother B-Organization
Kingdom I-Organization
; O
I O
mean O
what O
their O
reciprocal O
Duties O
to O
each O
other O
are O
, O
and O
what O
Obedience O
is O
due O
from O
the O
Children O
to O
the O
general O
Parent O
. O

The O
planting O
Colonies O
from O
Britain B-Organization
is O
but O
of O
recent O
Date O
, O
and O
nothing O
relative O
to O
such O
Plantation O
can O
be O
collected O
from O
the O
ancient O
Laws O
of O
the O
Kingdom B-Organization
; O
neither O
can O
we O
receive O
any O
better O
Information O
by O
extending O
our O
Inquiry O
into O
the O
History O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
established O
by O
the O
several O
Nations O
in O
the O
more O
early O
Ages O
of O
the O
World O
. O

All O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
( O
except O
those O
of O
Georgia B-Location
and O
Nova B-Location
Scotia I-Location
) O
formed O
from O
the O
English B-Organization
Nation I-Organization
, O
in O
North B-Location
America I-Location
, O
were O
planted O
in O
a O
Manner O
, O
and O
under O
a O
Dependence O
, O
of O
which O
there O
is O
not O
an O
Instance O
in O
all O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
of O
the O
Ancients O
; O
and O
therefore O
, O
I O
conceive O
, O
it O
must O
afford O
a O
good O
Degree O
of O
Surprise O
to O
find O
an O
English O
Civilian9 O
giving O
it O
as O
his O
Sentiment O
that O
the O
English B-Organization
Colonies I-Organization
ought O
to O
be O
governed O
by O
the O
Roman O
Laws O
, O
and O
for O
no O
better O
Reason O
than O
because O
the O
Spanish B-Organization
Colonies I-Organization
, O
as O
he O
says O
, O
are O
governed O
by O
those O
Laws O
. O

The O
Romans O
established O
their O
Colonies B-Organization
in O
the O
Midst O
of O
vanquished O
Nations O
, O
upon O
Principles O
which O
best O
secured O
their O
Conquests O
; O
the O
Privileges O
granted O
to O
them O
were O
not O
always O
the O
same O
; O
their O
Policy O
in O
the O
Government O
of O
their O
Colonies O
and O
the O
conquered O
Nations O
being O
always O
directed O
by O
arbitrary O
Principles O
to O
the O
End O
they O
aimed O
at O
, O
the O
subjecting O
the O
whole O
Earth O
to O
their O
Empire B-Organization
. O

But O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
in I-Organization
North I-Organization
America I-Organization
, O
except O
those O
planted O
within O
the O
present O
Century O
, O
were O
founded O
by O
Englishmen O
; O
who O
, O
becoming O
private O
Adventurers O
, O
established O
themselves O
, O
without O
any O
Expense O
to O
the O
Nation B-Organization
, O
in O
this O
uncultivated O
and O
almost O
uninhabited O
Country B-Organization
; O
so O
that O
their O
Case O
is O
plainly O
distinguishable O
from O
that O
of O
the O
Roman B-Organization
, O
or O
any O
other O
Colonies O
of O
the O
ancient O
World O
. O

As O
then O
we O
can O
receive O
no O
Light O
from O
the O
Laws O
of O
the O
Kingdom B-Organization
, O
or O
from O
ancient O
History O
, O
to O
direct O
us O
in O
our O
Inquiry O
, O
we O
must O
have O
Recourse O
to O
the O
Law O
of O
Nature O
, O
and O
those O
Rights O
of O
Mankind O
which O
flow O
from O
it O
. O

I O
have O
observed O
before O
that O
when O
Subjects O
are O
deprived O
of O
their O
civil O
Rights O
, O
or O
are O
dissatisfied O
with O
the O
Place O
they O
hold O
in O
the O
Community O
, O
they O
have O
a O
natural O
Right O
to O
quit O
the O
Society O
of O
which O
they O
are O
Members O
, O
and O
to O
retire O
into O
another O
Country O
. O

Now O
when O
Men O
exercise O
this O
Right O
, O
and O
withdraw O
themselves O
from O
their O
Country O
, O
they O
recover O
their O
natural O
Freedom O
and O
Independence O
: O
The O
Jurisdiction O
and O
Sovereignty O
of O
the O
State O
they O
have O
quitted O
ceases O
; O
and O
if O
they O
unite O
, O
and O
by O
common O
Consent O
take O
Possession O
of O
a O
new O
Country O
, O
and O
form O
themselves O
into O
a O
political O
Society O
, O
they O
become O
a O
sovereign O
State O
, O
independent O
of O
the O
State O
from O
which O
they O
separated O
. O

If O
then O
the O
Subjects O
of O
England B-Location
have O
a O
natural O
Right O
to O
relinquish O
their O
Country B-Organization
, O
and O
by O
retiring O
from O
it O
, O
and O
associating O
together O
, O
to O
form O
a O
new O
political O
Society O
and O
independent O
State O
, O
they O
must O
have O
a O
Right O
, O
by O
Compact O
with O
the O
Sovereign B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Nation I-Organization
, O
to O
remove O
into O
a O
new O
Country O
, O
and O
to O
form O
a O
civil O
Establishment O
upon O
the O
Terms O
of O
the O
Compact O
. O

In O
such O
a O
Case O
, O
the O
Terms O
of O
the O
Compact O
must O
be O
obligatory O
and O
binding O
upon O
the O
Parties O
; O
they O
must O
be O
the O
Magna O
Charta O
, O
the O
fundamental O
Principles O
of O
Government O
, O
to O
this O
new O
Society O
; O
and O
every O
Infringement O
of O
them O
must O
be O
wrong O
, O
and O
may O
be O
opposed O
. O

It O
will O
be O
necessary O
then O
to O
examine O
whether O
any O
such O
Compact O
was O
entered O
into O
between O
the O
Sovereign B-Organization
and O
those O
English O
Subjects O
who O
established O
themselves O
in O
America B-Location
. O

You O
have O
told O
us O
that O
“ O
before O
the O
first O
and O
great O
Act O
of O
Navigation O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
North B-Location
America I-Location
were O
but O
a O
few O
unhappy O
Fugitives O
, O
who O
had O
wandered O
thither O
to O
enjoy O
their O
civil O
and O
religious O
Liberties O
, O
which O
they O
were O
deprived O
of O
at O
Home O
. O
” O

If O
this O
was O
true O
, O
it O
is O
evident O
, O
from O
what O
has O
been O
said O
upon O
the O
Law O
of O
Nature O
, O
that O
they O
have O
a O
Right O
to O
a O
civil O
independent O
Establishment O
of O
their O
own O
, O
and O
that O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
has O
no O
Right O
to O
interfere O
in O
it O
. O

But O
you O
have O
been O
guilty O
of O
a O
gross O
Anachronism O
in O
your O
Chronology O
, O
and O
a O
great O
Errour O
in O
your O
Account O
of O
the O
first O
Settlement O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
in I-Organization
North I-Organization
America I-Organization
; O
for O
it O
is O
a O
notorious O
Fact O
that O
they O
were O
not O
settled O
by O
Fugitives O
from O
their O
native O
Country B-Organization
, O
but O
by O
Men O
who O
came O
over O
voluntarily O
, O
at O
their O
own O
Expense O
, O
and O
under O
Charters O
from O
the O
Crown B-Organization
, O
obtained O
for O
that O
Purpose O
, O
long O
before O
the O
first O
and O
great O
Act O
of O
Navigation O
. O

The O
first O
of O
these O
Charters O
was O
granted O
to O
Sir B-Person
Walter I-Person
Raleigh I-Person
by O
Queen B-Person
Elizabeth I-Person
under O
her O
great O
Seal O
, O
and O
was O
confirmed O
by O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
of I-Organization
England I-Organization
in O
the O
Year O
1684.10 O
By O
this O
Charter O
the O
whole O
Country B-Organization
to O
be O
possessed O
by O
Sir B-Person
Walter I-Person
Raleigh I-Person
was O
granted O
to O
him O
, O
his O
Heirs O
and O
Assigns O
, O
in O
perpetual O
Sovereignty O
, O
in O
as O
extensive O
a O
Manner O
as O
the O
Crown O
could O
grant O
, O
or O
had O
ever O
granted O
before O
to O
any O
Person O
or O
Persons O
, O
with O
full O
Power O
of O
Legislation O
, O
and O
to O
establish O
a O
civil O
Government O
in O
it O
as O
near O
as O
conveniently O
might O
be O
agreeable O
to O
the O
Form O
of O
the O
English B-Organization
Government I-Organization
and O
Policy O
thereof O
. O

The O
Country B-Organization
was O
to O
be O
united O
to O
the O
Realm B-Organization
of I-Organization
England I-Organization
in O
perfect O
LEAGUE O
AND O
AMITY O
, O
was O
to O
be O
within O
the O
Allegiance O
of O
the O
Crown B-Organization
of I-Organization
England I-Organization
, O
and O
to O
be O
held O
by O
Homage O
, O
and O
the O
Payment O
of O
one O
Fifth O
of O
all O
Gold O
and O
Silver O
Ore O
, O
which O
was O
reserved O
for O
all O
Services O
, O
Duties O
, O
and O
Demands O
. O

Sir B-Person
Walter I-Person
Raleigh I-Person
, O
under O
this O
Charter O
, O
took O
Possession O
of O
North B-Location
America I-Location
, O
upon O
that O
Part O
of O
the O
Continent B-Location
which O
gave O
him O
a O
Right O
to O
the O
Tract O
of O
Country O
which O
lies O
between O
the O
twenty O
fifth O
Degree O
of O
Latitude O
and O
the O
Gulf O
of O
St O
. O

Laurence B-Location
; O
but O
a O
Variety O
of O
Accidents O
happening O
in O
the O
Course O
of O
his O
Exertions O
to O
establish O
a O
Colony O
, O
and O
perhaps O
being O
overborn O
by O
the O
Expense O
of O
so O
great O
a O
Work O
, O
he O
made O
an O
Assignment O
to O
divers O
Gentlemen O
and O
Merchants O
of O
London B-Location
, O
in O
the O
31st O
Year O
of O
the O
Queen B-Person
’ O
s O
Reign O
, O
for O
continuing O
his O
Plantation O
in O
America B-Location
. O

These O
Assignees O
were O
not O
more O
successful O
in O
their O
Attempts O
than O
the O
Proprietor O
himself O
had O
been O
; O
but O
being O
animated O
with O
the O
Expectation O
of O
mighty O
Advantages O
from O
the O
Accomplishment O
of O
their O
Undertaking O
, O
they O
, O
with O
others O
, O
who O
associated O
with O
them O
, O
obtained O
new O
Charters O
from O
King B-Person
James I-Person
the I-Person
First I-Person
, O
in O
whom O
all O
Sir B-Person
Walter I-Person
Raleigh I-Person
’ O
s O
Rights O
became O
vested O
upon O
his O
Attainder O
; O
containing O
the O
same O
extensive O
Jurisdictions O
, O
Royalties O
, O
Privileges O
, O
Franchises O
, O
and O
Preeminences O
, O
and O
the O
same O
Powers O
to O
establish O
a O
civil O
Government O
in O
the O
Colony O
, O
as O
had O
been O
granted O
to O
Sir B-Person
W I-Person
. I-Person

Raleigh B-Person
, O
with O
an O
express O
Clause O
of O
Exemption O
for O
ever O
from O
all O
Taxes O
or O
Impositions O
upon O
their O
Import O
and O
Export O
Trade O
. O

Under O
these O
Charters O
the O
Proprietors O
effectually O
prosecuted O
, O
and O
happily O
succeeded O
, O
in O
planting O
a O
Colony O
upon O
that O
Part O
of O
the O
Continent B-Location
which O
is O
now O
called O
Virginia B-Location
. O

This O
Colony B-Organization
, O
after O
struggling O
through O
immense O
Difficulties O
, O
without O
receiving O
the O
least O
Assistance O
from O
the O
English B-Organization
Government I-Organization
, O
attained O
to O
such O
a O
Degree O
of O
Perfection O
that O
in O
the O
Year O
1621 O
a O
General B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
, O
or O
legislative O
Authority O
, O
was O
established O
in O
the O
Governour B-Organization
, O
Council B-Organization
, O
and O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Burgesses I-Organization
, O
who O
were O
elected O
by O
the O
Freeholders O
as O
their O
Representatives B-Organization
; O
and O
they O
have O
continued O
from O
that O
Time O
to O
exercise O
the O
Power O
of O
Legislation O
over O
the O
Colony B-Organization
. O

But O
upon O
the O
15th O
of O
July O
, O
1624 O
, O
King B-Person
James I-Person
dissolved O
the O
Company B-Organization
by O
Proclamation O
, O
and O
took O
the O
Colony O
under O
his O
immediate O
Dependence O
; O
which O
occasioned O
much O
Confusion O
, O
and O
created O
mighty O
Apprehensions O
in O
the O
Colony B-Location
lest O
they O
should O
be O
deprived O
of O
the O
Rights O
and O
Privileges O
granted O
them O
by O
the O
Company B-Organization
, O
according O
to O
the O
Powers O
contained O
in O
their O
Charters O
. O

To O
put O
an O
End O
to O
this O
Confusion O
, O
and O
to O
conciliate O
the O
Colony B-Organization
to O
the O
new O
System O
of O
Government O
the O
Crown B-Organization
intended O
to O
establish O
among O
them O
, O
K O
. O

Charles B-Person
the I-Person
First I-Person
, O
upon O
the O
Demise O
of O
his O
Father O
, O
by O
Proclamation O
the O
13th O
of O
May O
, O
1625 O
, O
declared O
“ O
that O
Virginia B-Organization
should O
be O
immediately O
dependent O
upon O
the O
Crown B-Organization
; O
that O
the O
Affairs O
of O
the O
Colony B-Organization
should O
be O
vested O
in O
a O
Council B-Organization
, O
consisting O
of O
a O
few O
Persons O
of O
Understanding O
and O
Quality O
, O
to O
be O
subordinate O
and O
attendant O
to O
the O
Privy B-Organization
Council I-Organization
in I-Organization
England I-Organization
; O
that O
he O
was O
resolved O
to O
establish O
another O
Council B-Organization
in I-Organization
Virginia I-Organization
, O
to O
be O
subordinate O
to O
the O
Council B-Organization
in I-Organization
England I-Organization
for O
the O
Colony B-Organization
; O
and O
that O
he O
would O
maintain O
the O
necessary O
Officers O
, O
Ministers O
, O
Forces O
, O
Ammunition O
, O
and O
Fortifications O
thereof O
, O
at O
his O
own O
Charge O
. O
” O

But O
this O
Proclamation O
had O
an O
Effect O
quite O
different O
from O
what O
was O
intended O
; O
instead O
of O
allaying O
, O
it O
increased O
the O
Confusion O
of O
the O
Colony B-Organization
; O
they O
now O
thought O
their O
regular O
Constitution O
was O
to O
be O
destroyed O
, O
and O
a O
Prerogative B-Organization
Government I-Organization
established O
over O
them O
; O
or O
, O
as O
they O
express O
themselves O
in O
their O
Remonstrance O
, O
that O
“ O
their O
Rights O
and O
Privileges O
were O
to O
be O
assaulted O
. O
” O

This O
general O
Disquietude O
and O
Dissatisfaction O
continued O
until O
they O
received O
a O
Letter O
from O
the O
Lords B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Privy I-Organization
Council I-Organization
, O
dated O
July O
the O
22d O
, O
1634 O
, O
containing O
the O
Royal O
Assurance O
and O
Confirmation O
that O
“ O
all O
their O
Estates O
, O
Trade O
, O
Freedom O
, O
and O
Privileges O
, O
should O
be O
enjoyed O
by O
them O
in O
as O
extensive O
a O
Manner O
as O
they O
enjoyed O
them O
before O
the O
recalling O
the O
Company B-Organization
’ O
s O
Patent O
; O
” O
whereupon O
they O
became O
reconciled O
, O
and O
began O
again O
to O
exert O
themselves O
in O
the O
Improvement O
of O
the O
Colony B-Organization
. O

Being O
now O
in O
full O
Possession O
of O
the O
Rights O
and O
Privileges O
of O
Englishmen O
, O
which O
they O
esteemed O
more O
than O
their O
Lives O
, O
their O
Affection O
for O
the O
Royal B-Organization
Government I-Organization
grew O
almost O
to O
Enthusiasm O
; O
for O
upon O
an O
Attempt O
to O
restore O
the O
Company B-Organization
’ O
s O
Charter O
by O
Authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
the O
General B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
, O
upon O
the O
1st O
of O
April O
, O
1642 O
, O
drew O
up O
a O
Declaration O
or O
Protestation O
, O
in O
the O
Form O
of O
an O
Act O
, O
by O
which O
they O
declared O
“ O
they O
never O
would O
submit O
to O
the O
Government O
of O
any O
Company O
or O
Proprietor O
, O
or O
to O
so O
unnatural O
a O
Distance O
as O
a O
Company O
or O
other O
Person O
to O
interpose O
between O
the O
Crown B-Organization
and O
the O
Subjects O
; O
that O
they O
were O
born O
under O
Monarchy O
, O
and O
would O
never O
degenerate O
from O
the O
Condition O
of O
their O
Births O
by O
being O
subject O
to O
any O
other O
Government O
; O
and O
every O
Person O
who O
should O
attempt O
to O
reduce O
them O
under O
any O
other O
Government O
was O
declared O
an O
Enemy O
to O
the O
Country B-Organization
, O
and O
his O
Estate O
was O
to O
be O
forfeited O
. O
” O

This O
Act O
, O
being O
presented O
to O
the O
King B-Person
at O
his O
Court B-Organization
at I-Organization
York I-Organization
, O
July O
5th O
, O
1644 O
, O
drew O
from O
him O
a O
most O
gracious O
Answer O
, O
under O
his O
Royal O
Signet O
, O
in O
which O
he O
gave O
them O
the O
fullest O
Assurances O
that O
they O
should O
be O
always O
immediately O
dependent O
upon O
the O
Crown B-Organization
, O
and O
that O
the O
Form O
of O
Government O
should O
never O
be O
changed O
. O

But O
after O
the O
King B-Location
’ O
s O
Death O
they O
gave O
a O
more O
eminent O
Instance O
of O
their O
Attachment O
to O
Royal B-Organization
Government I-Organization
, O
in O
their O
Opposition O
to O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
and O
forcing O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
Commissioners I-Organization
, O
who O
were O
sent O
over O
with O
a O
Squadron O
of O
Ships O
of O
War O
to O
take O
Possession O
of O
the O
Country B-Organization
, O
into O
Articles O
of O
Surrender O
, O
before O
they O
would O
submit O
to O
their O
Obedience O
. O

As O
these O
Articles O
reflect O
no O
small O
Honour O
upon O
this O
Infant O
Colony B-Organization
, O
and O
as O
they O
are O
not O
commonly O
known O
, O
I O
will O
give O
an O
Abstract O
of O
such O
of O
them O
as O
relate O
to O
the O
present O
Subject O
. O
1 O
. O

The O
Plantation B-Organization
of I-Organization
Virginia I-Organization
, O
and O
all O
the O
Inhabitants O
thereof O
, O
shall O
be O
and O
remain O
in O
due O
Subjection O
to O
the O
Commonwealth B-Organization
of I-Organization
England I-Organization
, O
not O
as O
a O
conquered O
Country O
, O
but O
as O
a O
Country O
submitting O
by O
their O
own O
voluntary O
Act O
, O
and O
shall O
enjoy O
such O
Freedoms O
and O
Privileges O
as O
belong O
to O
the O
free O
People O
of O
England B-Location
. O
2 O
. O

The O
General B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
as O
formerly O
shall O
convene O
, O
and O
transact O
the O
Affairs O
of O
the O
Colony B-Organization
. O
3 O
. O

The O
People O
of O
Virginia B-Location
shall O
have O
a O
free O
Trade O
, O
as O
the O
People O
of O
England B-Location
, O
to O
all O
Places O
, O
and O
with O
all O
Nations O
. O
4 O
. O

Virginia B-Location
shall O
be O
free O
from O
all O
Taxes O
, O
Customs O
, O
and O
Impositions O
whatsoever O
; O
and O
none O
shall O
be O
imposed O
on O
them O
without O
Consent O
of O
the O
General B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
; O
and O
that O
neither O
Forts O
nor O
Castles O
be O
erected O
, O
or O
Garrisons O
maintained O
, O
without O
their O
Consent O
. O

Upon O
this O
Surrender O
of O
the O
Colony B-Organization
to O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
Sir B-Person
W I-Person
. I-Person

Berkley B-Person
, O
the O
Royal B-Organization
Governour I-Organization
, O
was O
removed O
, O
and O
three O
other O
Governours B-Organization
were O
successively O
elected O
by O
the O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Burgesses I-Organization
; O
but O
in O
January O
1659 O
Sir B-Person
William I-Person
Berkeley I-Person
was O
replaced O
at O
the O
Head B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Government I-Organization
by O
the O
People O
, O
who O
unanimously O
renounced O
their O
Obedience O
to O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
and O
restored O
the O
Royal O
Authority O
by O
proclaiming O
Charles B-Person
the I-Person
2d I-Person
King B-Organization
of I-Organization
England I-Organization
, I-Organization
Scotland I-Organization
, I-Organization
France I-Organization
, I-Organization
Ireland I-Organization
, I-Organization
and I-Organization
Virginia I-Organization
; O
so O
that O
he O
was O
King B-Organization
in I-Organization
Virginia I-Organization
some O
Time O
before O
he O
had O
any O
certain O
Assurance O
of O
being O
restored O
to O
his O
Throne B-Organization
in I-Organization
England I-Organization
. O

From O
this O
Detail O
of O
the O
Charters O
, O
and O
other O
Acts O
of O
the O
Crown B-Organization
, O
under O
which O
the O
first O
Colony B-Organization
in O
North B-Location
America I-Location
was O
established O
, O
it O
is O
evident O
that O
“ O
the O
Colonists O
were O
not O
a O
few O
unhappy O
Fugitives O
who O
had O
wandered O
into O
a O
distant O
Part O
of O
the O
World O
to O
enjoy O
their O
civil O
and O
religious O
Liberties O
, O
which O
they O
were O
deprived O
of O
at O
home O
, O
” O
but O
had O
a O
regular O
Government O
long O
before O
the O
first O
Act O
of O
Navigation O
, O
and O
were O
respected O
as O
a O
distinct O
State O
, O
independent O
, O
as O
to O
their O
internal O
Government B-Organization
, O
of O
the O
original O
Kingdom B-Organization
, O
but O
united O
with O
her O
, O
as O
to O
their O
external O
Polity O
, O
in O
the O
closest O
and O
most O
intimate O
LEAGUE O
AND O
AMITY O
, O
under O
the O
same O
Allegiance O
, O
and O
enjoying O
the O
Benefits O
of O
a O
reciprocal O
Intercourse O
. O

But O
allow O
me O
to O
make O
a O
Reflection O
or O
two O
upon O
the O
preceding O
Account O
of O
the O
first O
Settlement O
of O
an O
English O
Colony B-Organization
in O
North B-Location
America I-Location
. O

America B-Location
was O
no O
Part O
of O
the O
Kingdom B-Organization
of I-Organization
England I-Organization
; O
it O
was O
possessed O
by O
a O
savage O
People O
, O
scattered O
through O
the O
Country B-Location
, O
who O
were O
not O
subject O
to O
the O
English B-Organization
Dominion I-Organization
, O
nor O
owed O
Obedience O
to O
its O
Laws O
. O

This O
independent O
Country B-Location
was O
settled O
by O
Englishmen O
at O
their O
own O
Expense O
, O
under O
particular O
Stipulations O
with O
the O
Crown B-Organization
: O
These O
Stipulations O
then O
must O
be O
the O
sacred O
Band O
of O
Union O
between O
England B-Organization
and O
her O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
and O
cannot O
be O
infringed O
without O
Injustice O
. O

But O
you O
Object O
that O
“ O
no O
Power O
can O
abridge O
the O
Authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
which O
has O
never O
exempted O
any O
from O
the O
Submission O
they O
owe O
to O
it O
; O
and O
no O
other O
Power O
can O
grant O
such O
an O
Exemption O
. O
” O

I O
will O
not O
dispute O
the O
Authority O
of O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
which O
is O
without O
Doubt O
supreme O
within O
the O
Body O
of O
the O
Kingdom B-Organization
, O
and O
cannot O
be O
abridged O
by O
any O
other O
Power O
; O
but O
may O
not O
the O
King B-Organization
have O
Prerogatives O
which O
he O
has O
a O
Right O
to O
exercise O
without O
the O
Consent O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
? O

If O
he O
has O
, O
perhaps O
that O
of O
granting O
License O
to O
his O
Subjects O
to O
remove O
into O
a O
new O
Country O
, O
and O
to O
settle O
therein O
upon O
particular O
Conditions O
, O
may O
be O
one O
. O

If O
he O
has O
no O
such O
Prerogative O
, O
I O
cannot O
discover O
how O
the O
Royal O
Engagements O
can O
be O
made O
good O
, O
that O
“ O
the O
Freedom O
and O
other O
Benefits O
of O
the O
British O
Constitution O
” O
shall O
be O
secured O
to O
those O
People O
who O
shall O
settle O
in O
a O
new O
Country O
under O
such O
Engagements O
; O
the O
Freedom O
, O
and O
other O
Benefits O
of O
the O
British O
Constitution O
, O
cannot O
be O
secured O
to O
a O
People O
without O
they O
are O
exempted O
from O
being O
taxed O
by O
any O
Authority O
but O
that O
of O
their O
Representatives O
, O
chosen O
by O
themselves O
. O

This O
is O
an O
essential O
Part O
of O
British O
Freedom O
; O
but O
if O
the O
King B-Organization
cannot O
grant O
such O
an O
Exemption O
, O
in O
Right O
of O
his O
Prerogative O
, O
the O
Royal O
Promises O
cannot O
be O
fulfilled O
; O
and O
all O
Charters O
which O
have O
been O
granted O
by O
our O
former O
Kings B-Person
, O
for O
this O
Purpose O
, O
must O
be O
Deceptions O
upon O
the O
Subjects O
who O
accepted O
them O
, O
which O
to O
say O
would O
be O
a O
high O
Reflection O
upon O
the O
Honour O
of O
the O
Crown B-Organization
. O

But O
there O
was O
a O
Time O
when O
some O
Parts O
of O
England B-Location
itself O
were O
exempt O
from O
the O
Laws O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
: O
The O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
County B-Location
Palatine I-Location
of I-Location
Chester I-Location
were O
not O
subject O
to O
such O
Laws11 O
ab O
antiquo O
, O
because O
they O
did O
not O
send O
Representatives O
to O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
but O
had O
their O
own O
Commune B-Organization
Concilium I-Organization
; O
by O
whose O
Authority O
, O
with O
the O
Consent O
of O
their O
Earl O
, O
their O
Laws O
were O
made O
. O

If O
this O
Exemption O
was O
not O
derived O
originally O
from O
the O
Crown B-Organization
, O
it O
must O
have O
arisen O
from O
that O
great O
Principle O
in O
the O
British O
Constitution O
by O
which O
the O
Freemen O
in O
the O
Nation B-Location
are O
not O
subject O
to O
any O
Laws O
but O
such O
as O
are O
made O
by O
Representatives O
elected O
by O
themselves O
to O
Parliament B-Organization
; O
so O
that O
, O
in O
either O
Case O
, O
it O
is O
an O
Instance O
extremely O
applicable O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
who O
contend O
for O
no O
other O
Right O
but O
that O
of O
directing O
their O
internal O
Government O
by O
Laws O
made O
with O
their O
own O
Consent O
, O
which O
has O
been O
preserved O
to O
them O
by O
repeated O
Acts O
and O
Declarations O
of O
the O
Crown B-Organization
. O

The O
Constitution O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
being O
established O
upon O
the O
Principles O
of O
British O
Liberty O
, O
has O
never O
been O
infringed O
by O
the O
immediate O
Act O
of O
the O
Crown B-Organization
; O
but O
the O
Powers O
of O
Government O
, O
agreeably O
to O
this O
Constitution O
, O
have O
been O
constantly O
declared O
in O
the O
King B-Person
’ O
s O
Commissions O
to O
their O
Governours B-Organization
, O
which O
, O
as O
often O
as O
they O
pass O
the O
Great O
Seal O
, O
are O
new O
Declarations O
and O
Confirmations O
of O
the O
Rights O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
. O

Even O
in O
the O
Reign O
of O
Charles B-Person
the I-Person
Second I-Person
, O
a O
Time O
by O
no O
Means O
favourable O
to O
Liberty O
, O
these O
Rights O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
were O
maintained O
inviolate O
; O
for O
when O
it O
was O
thought O
necessary O
to O
establish O
a O
permanent O
Revenue O
for O
the O
Support O
of O
Government B-Organization
in I-Organization
Virginia I-Organization
, O
the O
King B-Person
did O
not O
apply O
to O
the O
English B-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
, O
but O
to O
the O
General B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
, O
and O
sent O
over O
an O
Act O
, O
under O
the O
Great O
Seal O
of O
England B-Organization
, O
by O
which O
it O
was O
enacted O
“ O
by O
the O
King B-Person
’ I-Person
s I-Person
Most I-Person
Excellent I-Person
Majesty I-Person
, O
by O
and O
with O
the O
Consent O
of O
the O
General B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
, O
” O
that O
two O
Shillings O
per O
Hogshead O
upon O
all O
Tobacco O
exported O
, O
one O
Shilling O
and O
Threepence O
per O
Tun O
upon O
Shipping O
, O
and O
Sixpence O
per O
Poll O
for O
every O
Person O
imported O
, O
not O
being O
actually O
a O
Mariner O
in O
Pay O
, O
were O
to O
be O
paid O
for O
ever O
as O
a O
Revenue O
for O
the O
Support O
of O
the O
Government B-Organization
in I-Organization
the I-Organization
Colony I-Organization
. O

I O
have O
taken O
Notice O
of O
this O
Act O
, O
not O
only O
because O
it O
shows O
the O
proper O
Fountain O
from O
whence O
all O
Supplies O
to O
be O
raised O
in O
the O
Colonies B-Location
ought O
to O
flow O
, O
but O
also O
as O
it O
affords O
an O
Instance O
that O
Royalty B-Organization
itself O
did O
not O
disdain O
formerly O
to O
be O
named O
as O
a O
Part O
of O
the O
Legislature B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Colony I-Organization
; O
though O
now O
, O
to O
serve O
a O
Purpose O
destructive O
of O
their O
Rights O
, O
and O
to O
introduce O
Principles O
of O
Despotism O
unknown O
to O
a O
free O
Constitution O
, O
the O
Legislature B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Colonies I-Organization
are O
degraded O
even O
below O
the O
Corporation O
of O
a O
petty O
Borough O
in O
England B-Location
. O

It O
must O
be O
admitted O
that O
after O
the O
Restoration O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
lost O
that O
Liberty O
of O
Commerce O
with O
foreign O
Nations O
they O
had O
enjoyed O
before O
that O
Time O
. O

As O
it O
became O
a O
fundamental O
Law O
of O
the O
other O
States B-Organization
of I-Organization
Europe I-Organization
to O
prohibit O
all O
foreign O
Trade O
with O
their O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
England B-Organization
demanded O
such O
an O
exclusive O
Trade O
with O
her O
Colonies B-Organization
. O

This O
was O
effected O
by O
the O
Act O
of O
25th O
Charles B-Person
2d I-Person
, O
and O
some O
other O
subsequent O
Acts O
; O
which O
not O
only O
circumscribed O
the O
Trade O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
with O
foreign O
Nations O
within O
very O
narrow O
Limits O
, O
but O
imposed O
Duties O
upon O
several O
Articles O
of O
their O
own O
Manufactory O
exported O
from O
one O
Colony B-Organization
to O
another O
. O

These O
Acts O
, O
which O
imposed O
severer O
Restrictions O
upon O
the O
Trade O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
than O
were O
imposed O
upon O
the O
Trade O
of O
England B-Organization
, O
deprived O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
so O
far O
as O
these O
Restrictions O
extended O
, O
of O
the O
Privileges O
of O
English O
Subjects O
, O
and O
constituted O
an O
unnatural O
Difference O
between O
Men O
under O
the O
same O
Allegiance O
, O
born O
equally O
free O
, O
and O
entitled O
to O
the O
same O
civil O
Rights O
. O

In O
this O
Light O
did O
the O
People O
of O
Virginia B-Location
view O
the O
Act O
of O
25th O
Charles B-Person
2d I-Person
, O
when O
they O
sent O
Agents O
to O
the O
English B-Organization
Court I-Organization
to O
represent O
against O
“ O
Taxes O
and O
Impositions O
being O
laid O
on O
the O
Colony B-Organization
by O
any O
Authority O
but O
that O
of O
their O
General B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
. O
” O

The O
Right O
of O
imposing O
internal O
Duties O
upon O
their O
Trade O
by O
Authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
was O
then O
disputed O
, O
though O
you O
say O
it O
was O
never O
called O
into O
Question O
; O
and O
the O
Agents O
sent O
from O
Virginia B-Location
upon O
this O
Occasion O
obtained O
a O
Declaration O
from O
Charles B-Person
2d I-Person
the O
19th O
of O
April O
1676 O
, O
under O
his O
Privy O
Seal O
, O
that O
Impositions O
or O
“ O
Taxes O
ought O
not O
to O
be O
laid O
upon O
the O
Inhabitants O
and O
Proprietors O
of O
the O
Colony B-Location
but O
by O
the O
common O
Consent O
of O
the O
General B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
, O
except O
such O
Impositions O
as O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
should O
lay O
on O
the O
Commodities O
imported O
into O
England B-Location
from O
the O
Colony B-Location
: O
” O
And O
he O
ordered O
a O
Charter O
to O
be O
made O
out O
, O
and O
to O
pass O
the O
Great O
Seal O
, O
for O
securing O
this O
Right O
, O
among O
others O
, O
to O
the O
Colony B-Organization
. O

But O
whether O
the O
Act O
of O
25th O
Charles B-Person
2d I-Person
, O
or O
any O
of O
the O
other O
Acts O
, O
have O
been O
complained O
of O
as O
Infringements O
of O
the O
Rights O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
or O
not O
, O
is O
immaterial O
; O
for O
if O
a O
Man O
of O
superiour O
Strength O
takes O
my O
Coat O
from O
me O
, O
that O
cannot O
give O
him O
a O
Right O
to O
my O
Cloak O
, O
nor O
am O
I O
obliged O
to O
submit O
to O
be O
deprived O
of O
all O
my O
Estate O
because O
I O
may O
have O
given O
up O
some O
Part O
of O
it O
without O
Complaint O
. O

Besides O
, O
I O
have O
proved O
irrefragably O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
not O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
and O
consequently O
, O
upon O
your O
own O
Position O
, O
that O
no O
new O
Law O
can O
bind O
them O
that O
is O
made O
without O
the O
Concurrence O
of O
their O
Representatives B-Organization
; O
and O
if O
so O
, O
then O
every O
Act O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
that O
imposes O
internal O
Taxes O
upon O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
is O
an O
Act O
of O
Power O
, O
and O
not O
of O
Right O
. O

I O
must O
speak O
freely O
, O
I O
am O
considering O
a O
Question O
which O
affects O
the O
Rights O
of O
above O
two O
Millions O
of O
as O
loyal O
Subjects O
as O
belong O
to O
the O
British B-Organization
Crown I-Organization
, O
and O
must O
use O
Terms O
adequate O
to O
the O
Importance O
of O
it O
; O
I O
say O
that O
Power O
abstracted O
from O
Right O
cannot O
give O
a O
just O
Title O
to O
Dominion O
. O

If O
a O
Man O
invades O
my O
Property O
, O
he O
becomes O
an O
Aggressor O
, O
and O
puts O
himself O
into O
a O
State O
of O
War O
with O
me O
: O
I O
have O
a O
Right O
to O
oppose O
this O
Invader O
; O
if O
I O
have O
not O
Strength O
to O
repel O
him O
, O
I O
must O
submit O
, O
but O
he O
acquires O
no O
Right O
to O
my O
Estate O
which O
he O
has O
usurped O
. O

Whenever O
I O
recover O
Strength O
I O
may O
renew O
my O
Claim O
, O
and O
attempt O
to O
regain O
my O
Possession O
; O
if O
I O
am O
never O
strong O
enough O
, O
my O
Son O
, O
or O
his O
Son O
, O
may O
, O
when O
able O
, O
recover O
the O
natural O
Right O
of O
his O
Ancestor O
which O
has O
been O
unjustly O
taken O
from O
him O
. O

I O
hope O
I O
shall O
not O
be O
charged O
with O
Insolence O
, O
in O
delivering O
the O
Sentiments O
of O
an O
honest O
Mind O
with O
Freedom O
: O
I O
am O
speaking O
of O
the O
Rights O
of O
a O
People O
; O
Rights O
imply O
Equality O
in O
the O
Instances O
to O
which O
they O
belong O
, O
and O
must O
be O
treated O
without O
Respect O
to O
the O
Dignity O
of O
the O
Persons O
concerned O
in O
them O
. O

If O
“ O
the O
British B-Organization
Empire I-Organization
in I-Organization
Europe I-Organization
and O
in O
America B-Organization
is O
the O
same O
Power O
, O
” O
if O
the O
“ O
Subjects O
in O
both O
are O
the O
same O
People O
, O
and O
all O
equally O
participate O
in O
the O
Adversity O
and O
Prosperity O
of O
the O
Whole O
, O
” O
what O
Distinctions O
can O
the O
Difference O
of O
their O
Situations O
make O
, O
and O
why O
is O
this O
Distinction O
made O
between O
them O
? O

Why O
is O
the O
Trade O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
more O
circumscribed O
than O
the O
Trade O
of O
Britain B-Organization
? O

And O
why O
are O
Impositions O
laid O
upon O
the O
one O
which O
are O
not O
laid O
upon O
the O
other O
? O

If O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
“ O
have O
a O
Right O
to O
impose O
Taxes O
of O
every O
Kind O
upon O
the O
Colonies B-Location
, O
” O
they O
ought O
in O
Justice O
, O
as O
the O
same O
People O
, O
to O
have O
the O
same O
Sources O
to O
raise O
them O
from O
: O
Their O
Commerce O
ought O
to O
be O
equally O
free O
with O
the O
Commerce O
of O
Britain B-Organization
, O
otherwise O
it O
will O
be O
loading O
them O
with O
Burthens O
at O
the O
same O
Time O
that O
they O
are O
deprived O
of O
Strength O
to O
sustain O
them O
; O
it O
will O
be O
forcing O
them O
to O
make O
Bricks O
without O
Straw O
. O

I O
acknowledge O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
is O
the O
sovereign O
legislative O
Power O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Nation I-Organization
, O
and O
that O
by O
a O
full O
Exertion O
of O
their O
Power O
they O
can O
deprive O
the O
Colonists O
of O
the O
Freedom O
and O
other O
Benefits O
of O
the O
British O
Constitution O
which O
have O
been O
secured O
to O
them O
by O
our O
Kings B-Organization
; O
they O
can O
abrogate O
all O
their O
civil O
Rights O
and O
Liberties O
; O
but O
by O
what O
Right O
is O
it O
that O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
can O
exercise O
such O
a O
Power O
over O
the O
Colonists O
, O
who O
have O
as O
natural O
a O
Right O
to O
the O
Liberties O
and O
Privileges O
of O
Englishmen O
as O
if O
they O
were O
actually O
resident O
within O
the O
Kingdom B-Location
? O

The O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
subordinate O
to O
the O
Authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
; O
subordinate O
I O
mean O
in O
Degree O
, O
but O
not O
absolutely O
so O
: O
For O
if O
by O
a O
Vote O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Senate I-Organization
the O
Colonists O
were O
to O
be O
delivered O
up O
to O
the O
Rule O
of O
a O
French O
or O
Turkish O
Tyranny O
, O
they O
may O
refuse O
Obedience O
to O
such O
a O
Vote O
, O
and O
may O
oppose O
the O
Execution O
of O
it O
by O
Force O
. O

Great O
is O
the O
Power O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
but O
, O
great O
as O
it O
is O
, O
it O
cannot O
, O
constitutionally O
, O
deprive O
the O
People O
of O
their O
natural O
Rights O
; O
nor O
, O
in O
Virtue O
of O
the O
same O
Principle O
, O
can O
it O
deprive O
them O
of O
their O
civil O
Rights O
, O
which O
are O
founded O
in O
Compact O
, O
without O
their O
own O
Consent O
. O

There O
is O
, O
I O
confess O
, O
a O
considerable O
Difference O
between O
these O
two O
Cases O
as O
to O
the O
Right O
of O
Resistance O
: O
In O
the O
first O
, O
if O
the O
Colonists O
should O
be O
dismembered O
from O
the O
Nation B-Organization
by O
Act O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
and O
abandoned O
to O
another O
Power O
, O
they O
have O
a O
natural O
Right O
to O
defend O
their O
Liberties O
by O
open O
Force O
, O
and O
may O
lawfully O
resist O
; O
and O
, O
if O
they O
are O
able O
, O
repel O
the O
Power O
to O
whose O
Authority O
they O
are O
abandoned O
. O

But O
in O
the O
other O
, O
if O
they O
are O
deprived O
of O
their O
civil O
Rights O
, O
if O
great O
and O
manifest O
Oppressions O
are O
imposed O
upon O
them O
by O
the O
State B-Organization
on O
which O
they O
are O
dependent O
, O
their O
Remedy O
is O
to O
lay O
their O
Complaints O
at O
the O
Foot O
of O
the O
Throne B-Organization
, O
and O
to O
suffer O
patiently O
rather O
than O
disturb O
the O
publick O
Peace O
, O
which O
nothing O
but O
a O
Denial O
of O
Justice O
can O
excuse O
them O
in O
breaking O
. O

But O
if O
this O
Justice O
should O
be O
denied O
, O
if O
the O
most O
humble O
and O
dutiful O
Representations O
should O
be O
rejected O
, O
nay O
not O
even O
deigned O
to O
be O
received O
, O
what O
is O
to O
be O
done O
? O

To O
such O
a O
Question O
Thucydides B-Person
would O
make O
the O
Corinthians O
reply O
, O
that O
if O
“ O
a O
decent O
and O
condescending O
Behaviour O
is O
shown O
on O
the O
Part O
of O
the O
Colonies O
, O
it O
would O
be O
base O
in O
the O
Mother O
State O
to O
press O
too O
far O
on O
such O
Moderation O
: O
” O
And O
he O
would O
make O
the O
Corcyreans O
answer O
, O
that O
“ O
every O
Colony O
, O
whilst O
used O
in O
a O
proper O
Manner O
, O
ought O
to O
pay O
Honour O
and O
Regard O
to O
its O
Mother O
State O
; O
but O
, O
when O
treated O
with O
Injury O
and O
Violence O
, O
is O
become O
an O
Alien O
. O

They O
were O
not O
sent O
out O
to O
be O
the O
Slaves O
, O
but O
to O
be O
the O
Equals O
of O
those O
that O
remain O
behind O
. O
” O

But O
, O
according O
to O
your O
Scheme O
, O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
to O
be O
prohibited O
from O
uniting O
in O
a O
Representation O
of O
their O
general O
Grievances O
to O
the O
common B-Organization
Sovereign I-Organization
. O

This O
Moment O
“ O
the O
British B-Organization
Empire I-Organization
in I-Organization
Europe I-Organization
and O
in O
America B-Organization
is O
the O
same O
Power O
; O
its O
Subjects O
in O
both O
are O
the O
same O
People O
; O
each O
is O
equally O
important O
to O
the O
other O
, O
and O
mutual O
Benefits O
, O
mutual O
Necessities O
, O
cement O
their O
Connexion O
. O
” O

The O
next O
Moment O
“ O
the O
Colonies O
are O
unconnected O
with O
each O
other O
, O
different O
in O
their O
Manners O
, O
opposite O
in O
their O
Principles O
, O
and O
clash O
in O
their O
Interests O
and O
in O
their O
Views O
, O
from O
Rivalry O
in O
Trade O
, O
and O
the O
Jealousy O
of O
Neighbourhood O
. O

This O
happy O
Division O
, O
which O
was O
effected O
by O
Accident O
, O
is O
to O
be O
continued O
throughout O
by O
Design O
; O
and O
all O
Bond O
of O
Union O
between O
them O
” O
is O
excluded O
from O
your O
vast O
System O
. O

Divide O
et O
impera O
is O
your O
Maxim O
in O
Colony O
Administration O
, O
lest O
“ O
an O
Alliance O
should O
be O
formed O
dangerous O
to O
the O
Mother B-Organization
Country I-Organization
. O
” O

Ungenerous O
Insinuation O
! O

detestable O
Thought O
! O

abhorrent O
to O
every O
Native O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
! O

who O
, O
by O
an O
Uniformity O
of O
Conduct O
, O
have O
ever O
demonstrated O
the O
deepest O
Loyalty O
to O
their O
King B-Organization
, O
as O
the O
Father O
of O
his O
People O
, O
and O
an O
unshaken O
Attachment O
to O
the O
Interest O
of O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
. O

But O
you O
must O
entertain O
a O
most O
despicable O
Opinion O
of O
the O
Understandings O
of O
the O
Colonists O
to O
imagine O
that O
they O
will O
allow O
Divisions O
to O
be O
fomented O
between O
them O
about O
inconsiderable O
Things O
, O
when O
the O
closest O
Union O
becomes O
necessary O
to O
maintain O
in O
a O
constitutional O
Way O
their O
dearest O
Interests O
. O

Another O
Writer O
, O
12 O
fond O
of O
his O
new O
System O
of O
placing O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
as O
the O
Centre O
of O
Attraction O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
says O
that O
“ O
they O
must O
be O
guarded O
against O
having O
or O
forming O
any O
Principle O
of O
Coherence O
with O
each O
other O
above O
that O
whereby O
they O
cohere O
in O
the O
Centre O
; O
having O
no O
other O
Principle O
of O
Intercommunication O
between O
each O
other O
than O
that O
by O
which O
they O
are O
in O
joint O
Communication O
with O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
, O
as O
the O
common O
Centre O
of O
all O
. O

At O
the O
same O
Time O
that O
they O
are O
each O
, O
in O
their O
respective O
Parts O
and O
Subordinations O
, O
so O
framed O
as O
to O
be O
acted O
by O
this O
first O
Mover O
, O
they O
should O
always O
remain O
incapable O
of O
any O
Coherence O
, O
or O
of O
so O
conspiring O
amongst O
themselves O
as O
to O
create O
any O
other O
equal O
Force O
which O
might O
recoil O
back O
on O
this O
first O
Mover O
; O
nor O
is O
it O
more O
necessary O
to O
preserve O
the O
several O
Governments O
subordinate O
within O
their O
respective O
Orbs O
than O
it O
is O
essential O
to O
the O
Preservation O
of O
the O
Empire B-Organization
to O
keep O
them O
disconnected O
and O
independent O
of O
each O
other O
. O
” O

But O
how O
is O
this O
“ O
Principle O
of O
Coherence O
, O
” O
as O
this O
elegant O
Writer O
calls O
it O
, O
between O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
to O
be O
prevented O
? O

The O
Colonies B-Organization
upon O
the O
Continent B-Location
of I-Location
North I-Location
America I-Location
lie O
united O
to O
each O
other O
in O
one O
Tract O
of O
Country O
, O
and O
are O
equally O
concerned O
to O
maintain O
their O
common O
Liberty O
. O

If O
he O
will O
attend O
then O
to O
the O
Laws O
of O
Attraction O
in O
natural O
as O
well O
as O
political O
Philosophy O
, O
he O
will O
find O
that O
Bodies O
in O
Contact O
, O
and O
cemented O
by O
mutual O
Interests O
, O
cohere O
more O
strongly O
than O
those O
which O
are O
at O
a O
Distance O
, O
and O
have O
no O
common O
Interests O
to O
preserve O
. O

But O
this O
natural O
Law O
is O
to O
be O
destroyed O
; O
and O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
whose O
real O
Interests O
are O
the O
same O
, O
and O
therefore O
ought O
to O
be O
united O
in O
the O
closest O
Communication O
, O
are O
to O
be O
disjoined O
, O
and O
all O
Intercommunication O
between O
them O
prevented O
. O

But O
how O
is O
this O
System O
of O
Administration O
to O
be O
established O
? O

Is O
it O
to O
be O
done O
by O
a O
military O
Force O
, O
quartered O
upon O
private O
Families O
? O

Is O
it O
to O
be O
done O
by O
extending O
the O
Jurisdiction O
of O
Courts B-Organization
of I-Organization
Admiralty I-Organization
, O
and O
thereby O
depriving O
the O
Colonists O
of O
legal O
Trials O
in O
the O
Courts B-Organization
of I-Organization
common I-Organization
Law I-Organization
? O

Or O
is O
it O
to O
be O
done O
by O
harassing O
the O
Colonists O
, O
and O
giving O
overbearing O
Taxgatherers O
an O
Opportunity O
of O
ruining O
Men O
, O
perhaps O
better O
Subjects O
than O
themselves O
, O
by O
dragging O
them O
from O
one O
Colony O
to O
another O
, O
before O
Prerogative O
Judges O
, O
exercising O
a O
despotick O
Sway O
in O
Inquisitorial B-Organization
Courts I-Organization
? O

Oppression O
has O
produced O
very O
great O
and O
unexpected O
Events O
: O
The O
Helvetick B-Organization
Confederacy I-Organization
, O
the O
States B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
United I-Organization
Netherlands I-Organization
, O
are O
Instances O
in O
the O
Annals O
of O
Europe B-Location
of O
the O
glorious O
Actions O
a O
petty O
People O
, O
in O
Comparison O
, O
can O
perform O
when O
united O
in O
the O
Cause O
of O
Liberty O
. O

May O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
ever O
remain O
under O
a O
constitutional O
Subordination O
to O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
! O

It O
is O
their O
Interest O
to O
live O
under O
such O
a O
Subordination O
; O
and O
it O
is O
their O
Duty O
, O
by O
an O
Exertion O
of O
all O
their O
Strength O
and O
Abilities O
, O
when O
called O
upon O
by O
their O
common B-Organization
Sovereign I-Organization
, O
to O
advance O
the O
Grandeur O
and O
the O
Glory O
of O
the O
Nation B-Organization
. O

May O
the O
Interests O
of O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
and O
her O
Colonies B-Organization
be O
ever O
united O
, O
so O
as O
that O
whilst O
they O
are O
retained O
in O
a O
legal O
and O
just O
Dependence O
no O
unnatural O
or O
unlimited O
Rule O
may O
be O
exercised O
over O
them O
; O
but O
that O
they O
may O
enjoy O
the O
Freedom O
, O
and O
other O
Benefits O
of O
the O
British O
Constitution O
, O
to O
the O
latest O
Page O
in O
History O
! O

I O
flatter O
myself O
, O
by O
what O
has O
been O
said O
, O
your O
Position O
of O
a O
virtual O
Representation O
is O
sufficiently O
refuted O
; O
and O
that O
there O
is O
really O
no O
such O
Representation O
known O
in O
the O
British O
Constitution O
, O
and O
consequently O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Location
are O
not O
subject O
to O
an O
internal O
Taxation O
by O
Authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
. O

I O
could O
extend O
this O
Inquiry O
to O
a O
much O
greater O
Length O
, O
by O
examining O
into O
the O
Policy O
of O
the O
late O
Acts O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
which O
impose O
heavy O
and O
severe O
Taxes O
, O
Duties O
, O
and O
Prohibitions O
, O
upon O
the O
Colonies B-Location
; O
I O
could O
point O
out O
some O
very O
disagreeable O
Consequences O
, O
respecting O
the O
Trade O
and O
Manufactures O
of O
Britain B-Location
, O
which O
must O
necessarily O
result O
from O
these O
Acts O
; O
I O
could O
prove O
that O
the O
Revenues O
arising O
from O
the O
Trade O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
, O
and O
the O
Advantage O
of O
their O
Exports O
to O
Great B-Location
Britain I-Location
in O
the O
Balance O
of O
her O
Trade O
with O
foreign O
Nations O
, O
exceed O
infinitely O
all O
the O
Expense O
she O
has O
been O
at O
, O
all O
the O
Expense O
she O
can O
be O
at O
, O
in O
their O
Protection O
; O
and O
perhaps O
I O
could O
show O
that O
the O
Bounties O
given O
upon O
some O
Articles O
exported O
from O
the O
Colonies B-Location
were O
not O
intended O
, O
primarily O
, O
as O
Instances O
of O
Attention O
to O
their O
Interest O
, O
but O
arose O
as O
well O
from O
the O
Consideration O
of O
the O
disadvantageous O
Dependence O
of O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
upon O
other O
Nations O
for O
the O
principal O
Articles O
of O
her O
naval O
Stores O
, O
as O
from O
her O
losing O
Trade O
for O
those O
Articles O
; O
I O
could O
demonstrate O
that O
these O
Bounties O
are O
by O
no O
Means O
adequate O
to O
her O
Savings O
in O
such O
foreign O
Trade O
, O
if O
the O
Articles O
upon O
which O
they O
are O
given O
can O
be O
procured O
from O
the O
Colonies B-Location
in O
Quantities O
sufficient O
to O
answer O
her O
Consumption O
; O
and O
that O
the O
Excess O
of O
these O
Savings O
is O
so O
much O
clear O
Profit O
to O
the O
Nation B-Organization
, O
upon O
the O
Supposition O
that O
these O
Bounties O
are O
drawn O
from O
it O
; O
but O
, O
as O
they O
will O
remain O
in O
it O
, O
and O
be O
laid O
out O
in O
its O
Manufactures O
and O
Exports O
, O
that O
the O
whole O
Sum O
which O
used O
to O
be O
paid O
to O
Foreigners O
for O
the O
Purchase O
of O
these O
Articles O
will O
be O
saved O
to O
the O
Nation B-Organization
. O

I O
say O
I O
could O
extend O
my O
Inquiry O
, O
by O
examining O
these O
several O
Matters O
; O
but O
as O
the O
Subject O
is O
delicate O
, O
and O
would O
carry O
me O
to O
a O
great O
Length O
, O
I O
shall O
leave O
them O
to O
the O
Reader O
’ O
s O
own O
Reflection O
. O
1Petyt O
’ O
s O
Rights O
of O
the O
Com O
. O

Brady B-Person
’ O
s O
Comp O
. O

Hist O
. O

Rapin O
. O

Squire B-Person
’ O
s O
Inquiry O
. O
2Cæsar O
de O
Bell O
. O

Gall O
. O

Tacitus B-Person
de O
Germ O
. O

C O
. O
28 O
. O

Temple O
’ O
s O
Misc O
. O
Tacitus B-Person
4Ibid O
. O
52 O
de O
Germ O
. O

C O
. O
11 O
. O

C O
. O
25 O
. O

Inst O
. O
27 O
. O
4 O
Inst O
. O
2 O
. O
6Vattel O
’ O
s O
Law O
of O
Nature O
. O

Locke B-Person
on O
Civil O
Govern O
. O

Wollaston B-Person
’ O
s O
Rel O
. O
of O
Nat O
. O
7Wollaston O
’ O
s O
82 O
Rel O
. O
of O
Nat O
. O

Pur O
. O

Williams B-Person
. O
9Strahan O
in O
his O
Preface O
to O
Domat O
. O
10This O
Charter O
is O
printed O
at O
large O
in O
Hakluyt O
’ O
s O
Voyages O
, O
P O
. O
725 O
, O
Folio O
Edition O
, O
Anno O
1589 O
; O
and O
the O
Substance O
of O
it O
is O
in O
the O
3d O
Vol O
. O
of O
Salmon O
’ O
s O
Mod O
. O

Hist O
. O

P O
. O
424 O
. O
11Petyt O
’ O
s O
12The O
Rights O
of O
the O
Commons O
. O

King B-Organization
’ O
s O
Vale O
Royal O
of O
England B-Organization
. O

Administration O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
by O
Governour B-Person
Pownall I-Person
. O

