PAMPHLET O
7 O
[ O
Daniel B-Person
Dulany I-Person
] O
, O
Considerations O
on O
the O
Propriety O
of O
Imposing O
Taxes O
in O
the O
British B-Location
Colonies I-Location
, O
for O
the O
Purpose O
of O
Raising O
a O
Revenue O
, O
by O
Act O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
. O

[ O
Annapolis B-Location
] O
, O
1765 O
. O

Whately B-Person
’ O
s O
Regulations O
Lately O
Made O
was O
soon O
joined O
by O
other O
defenses O
of O
the O
Stamp O
Act O
, O
including O
The O
Objections O
to O
the O
Taxation O
of O
Our O
American B-Location
Colonies I-Location
. O
. O
. O

Considered O
by O
Soame B-Location
Jenyns I-Location
, O
a O
poet O
and O
former O
member O
of O
the O
Board B-Organization
of I-Organization
Trade I-Organization
, O
and O
The O
Claim O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
to O
an O
Exemption O
from O
Internal O
Taxes O
Imposed O
by O
Authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
Examined O
by O
William B-Person
Knox I-Person
, O
a O
former O
colonial O
official O
. O

Americans O
read O
these O
pamphlets O
with O
great O
interest O
and O
alarm O
, O
knowing O
that O
these O
assertions O
of O
parliamentary O
power O
had O
to O
be O
answered O
. O

The O
most O
formidable O
among O
the O
rejoinders O
was O
the O
following O
anonymous O
pamphlet O
. O

Its O
author O
was O
Daniel B-Person
Dulany I-Person
, O
son O
of O
a O
prominent O
and O
wealthy O
Maryland O
family O
, O
who O
had O
been O
educated O
at O
Cambridge B-Organization
and O
studied O
law O
at O
Middle B-Organization
Temple I-Organization
in O
London B-Location
before O
returning O
home O
to O
be O
admitted O
to O
the O
Maryland O
bar O
in O
1747 O
. O

Over O
the O
next O
two O
decades O
he O
enjoyed O
a O
number O
of O
elective O
and O
appointive O
positions O
in O
the O
colony B-Organization
, O
and O
in O
1765 O
he O
was O
its O
secretary B-Organization
, O
commissary B-Organization
general I-Organization
, O
and O
a O
member O
of O
the O
governor B-Organization
’ I-Organization
s I-Organization
council I-Organization
. O

In O
his O
pamphlet O
Dulany B-Person
did O
not O
actually O
repudiate O
the O
theory O
of O
virtual O
representation O
and O
its O
claim O
that O
certain O
people O
from O
society O
, O
if O
their O
interests O
were O
identical O
with O
the O
rest O
, O
could O
justly O
speak O
for O
the O
whole O
. O

For O
Dulany B-Person
, O
the O
fallacy O
in O
Whately B-Person
’ O
s O
contention O
lay O
not O
in O
the O
inability O
of O
the O
colonists O
to O
vote O
for O
members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
but O
rather O
in O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
interests O
of O
the O
English—electors O
, O
nonelectors O
, O
and O
representatives B-Organization
alike—were O
in O
no O
way O
identical O
with O
those O
of O
the O
colonists O
. O

In O
other O
words O
, O
he O
implied O
that O
Britons O
and O
Americans O
were O
not O
really O
one O
people O
after O
all O
. O

This O
pamphlet O
was O
quickly O
reprinted O
throughout O
the O
colonies B-Location
, O
and O
a O
London O
edition O
appeared O
the O
following O
year O
. O

Although O
he O
later O
became O
a O
Loyalist O
, O
in O
1765 O
Daniel B-Person
Dulany I-Person
’ O
s O
was O
one O
of O
the O
most O
important O
voices O
in O
support O
of O
the O
patriot O
cause O
. O

PREFACE O
. O

I O
T O
would O
, O
now O
, O
be O
an O
unfashionable O
Doctrine O
, O
whatever O
the O
ancient O
Opinion O
might O
be O
, O
to O
affirm O
that O
the O
Constituent O
can O
bind O
his O
Representative O
by O
Instructions O
; O
but O
tho O
’ O
the O
obligatory O
Force O
of O
these O
Instructions O
is O
not O
insisted O
upon O
, O
yet O
their O
persuasive O
Influence O
, O
in O
most O
Cases O
, O
may O
be O
; O
for O
a O
Representative O
, O
who O
should O
act O
against O
the O
explicit O
Recommendation O
of O
his O
Constituents O
, O
would O
most O
deservedly O
forfeit O
their O
Regard O
and O
all O
Pretension O
to O
their O
future O
Confidence O
. O

When O
it O
is O
under O
Deliberation O
, O
whether O
a O
new O
Law O
shall O
be O
Enacted O
, O
in O
which O
the O
Electors O
of O
England B-Location
are O
interested O
, O
THEY O
have O
Notice O
of O
it O
, O
and O
an O
Opportunity O
of O
declaring O
their O
Sense—THEY O
may O
point O
out O
every O
dangerous O
Tendency O
, O
and O
are O
not O
restrained O
in O
their O
Representations O
, O
from O
shewing O
in O
the O
plainest O
Language O
, O
the O
Injustice O
or O
Oppression O
of O
it O
. O

When O
a O
Law O
in O
it O
’ O
s O
Execution O
is O
found O
to O
be O
repugnant O
to O
the O
Genius O
of O
Liberty O
, O
or O
productive O
of O
Hardships O
or O
Inconvenience O
, O
THEY O
may O
also O
instruct O
their O
Deputies O
to O
exert O
Themselves O
in O
procuring O
a O
Repeal O
of O
it O
, O
and O
in O
the O
Exercise O
of O
this O
Right O
are O
not O
constrained O
to O
whine O
in O
the O
Style O
of O
humble O
Petitioners O
. O

— O
THEY O
are O
exposed O
to O
no O
Danger O
in O
explaining O
their O
Reasons—THEIR O
Situation O
does O
not O
become O
so O
delicate O
as O
to O
make O
it O
prudent O
, O
to O
weaken O
, O
by O
not O
urging O
them O
, O
with O
their O
full O
Force O
, O
and O
to O
their O
utmost O
Extent O
. O

But O
who O
are O
the O
Representatives B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Colonies I-Organization
? O

To O
whom O
shall O
THEY O
send O
their O
Instructions O
, O
when O
desirous O
to O
obtain O
the O
Repeal O
of O
a O
Law O
striking O
at O
the O
Root O
and O
Foundation O
of O
every O
Civil O
Right O
, O
should O
such O
an O
one O
take O
Place O
? O

Instructions O
to O
all O
the O
Members O
who O
compose O
the O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
would O
not O
be O
proper O
. O

To O
them O
the O
Application O
must O
be O
by O
Petition O
, O
in O
which O
an O
unreserved O
Style O
would O
, O
probably O
, O
be O
deemed O
Indecency O
, O
and O
strong O
Expressions O
Insolence O
, O
in O
which O
a O
Claim O
of O
Rights O
may O
not O
, O
perhaps O
, O
be O
explained O
, O
or O
even O
insinuated O
, O
if O
to O
impugn O
, O
or O
glance O
at O
their O
Authority O
whose O
Relief O
is O
supplicated O
. O

To O
soften O
and O
deprecate O
must O
be O
the O
Hope O
and O
Endeavour O
, O
tho O
’ O
a O
guiltless O
Freeman O
would O
, O
probably O
, O
be O
aukward O
in O
ringing O
all O
the O
Changes O
of O
Parce O
, O
Precor O
. O

Under O
these O
Circumstances O
, O
the O
Liberty O
of O
the O
Press O
is O
of O
the O
most O
momentous O
Consequence O
, O
for O
if O
Truth O
is O
not O
allowed O
to O
speak O
thence O
in O
it O
’ O
s O
genuine O
Language O
of O
Plainness O
and O
Simplicity O
, O
nor O
Freedom O
to O
vindicate O
it O
’ O
s O
Privileges O
with O
decent O
Firmness O
, O
we O
shall O
have O
too O
much O
Reason O
to O
acknowledge O
his O
Foresight O
who O
predicted O
, O
that O
, O
“ O
the O
Constitution O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Government I-Organization
was O
too O
excellent O
to O
be O
permament O
. O
” O

The O
Train O
for O
the O
Accomplishment O
of O
that O
Prophecy O
hath O
not O
yet O
catched O
in O
America B-Location
, O
nor O
, O
I O
trust O
, O
been O
laid O
. O

That O
there O
have O
been O
Laws O
extremely O
unjust O
and O
oppressive O
, O
the O
Declarations O
of O
subsequent O
Parliaments B-Organization
, O
fixing O
this O
Stigma O
upon O
them O
, O
evince O
; O
but O
whilst O
the O
Power O
which O
introduced O
them O
prevailed O
, O
it O
was O
not O
prudent O
to O
give O
them O
their O
deserved O
Characters O
. O

The O
Parliament B-Organization
of O
Henry B-Person
III I-Person
, O
or O
that O
of O
Henry B-Person
VI I-Person
, O
need O
not O
be O
cited O
; O
there O
are O
many O
other O
Instances O
, O
tho O
’ O
not O
branded O
with O
Epithets O
so O
remarkably O
opprobrious O
. O

In O
the O
Opinion O
of O
a O
great O
Lawyer O
, O
an O
Act O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
may O
be O
void O
, O
and O
of O
a O
great O
Divine O
, O
“ O
all O
Men O
have O
natural O
, O
and O
Freemen O
legal O
Rights O
, O
which O
they O
may O
justly O
maintain O
, O
and O
no O
legislative O
Authority O
can O
deprive O
them O
of O
. O
” O

Cases O
may O
be O
imagined O
in O
which O
the O
Truth O
of O
these O
Positions O
might O
, O
in O
Theory O
, O
be O
admitted O
; O
but O
in O
Practice O
, O
unless O
there O
should O
be O
very O
peculiar O
Circumstances O
, O
such O
as O
can O
’ O
t O
be O
supposed O
to O
exist O
during O
the O
Prevalence O
of O
the O
Power O
that O
introduced O
it O
, O
who O
would O
rely O
upon O
the O
Authority O
of O
Opinions O
, O
or O
the O
Principles O
of O
them O
, O
for O
his O
Protection O
against O
the O
Penalties O
of O
any O
positive O
Law O
? O

When O
the O
Judges O
were O
ask O
’ O
d O
by O
Henry B-Person
VIII I-Person
, O
Whether O
a O
Man O
might O
be O
attainted O
of O
High O
Treason O
by O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
tho O
’ O
not O
called O
to O
answer O
, O
they O
declared O
that O
it O
was O
a O
dangerous O
Question O
, O
and O
gave O
the O
evasive O
Answer O
that O
, O
“ O
the O
High B-Organization
Court I-Organization
of I-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
ought O
to O
give O
Examples O
of O
Justice O
to O
the O
inferior O
Courts O
, O
none O
of O
which O
could O
do O
the O
like O
. O
” O

But O
tho O
’ O
it O
might O
be O
dangerous O
to O
declare O
against O
the O
Authority O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
we O
are O
not O
bound O
to O
acknowledge O
it O
’ O
s O
Inerrability O
, O
nor O
precluded O
from O
examining O
the O
Principles O
and O
Consequences O
of O
Laws O
, O
or O
from O
pointing O
out O
their O
Improprieties O
, O
and O
Defects O
. O

Upon O
this O
Ground O
I O
have O
proceeded O
in O
the O
following O
Considerations O
, O
and O
shall O
not O
be O
disappointed O
if O
they O
should O
appear O
to O
be O
too O
free O
, O
or O
too O
reserved O
, O
to O
Readers O
of O
different O
Complexions O
. O

VIRGINIA O
, O
AUGUST O
12 O
, O
1765 O
. O

Considerations O
, O
& O
c O
. O

I O
N O
the O
Constitution O
of O
England B-Organization
, O
the O
Three O
principal O
Forms O
of O
Government O
, O
Monarchy O
, O
Aristocracy O
and O
Democracy O
, O
are O
blended O
together O
in O
certain O
Proportions O
; O
but O
each O
of O
these O
Orders O
, O
in O
the O
Exercise O
of O
the O
legislative O
Authority O
, O
hath O
its O
peculiar O
Department O
, O
from O
which O
the O
other O
are O
excluded O
. O

In O
this O
Division O
, O
the O
Granting O
of O
Supplies O
, O
or O
Laying O
Taxes O
, O
is O
deemed O
to O
be O
the O
Province O
of O
the O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
, O
as O
the O
Representative O
of O
the O
People O
. O

— O
All O
Supplies O
are O
supposed O
to O
flow O
from O
their O
Gift O
; O
and O
the O
other O
Orders O
are O
permitted O
only O
to O
assent O
, O
or O
reject O
generally O
, O
not O
to O
propose O
any O
Modification O
, O
Amendment O
, O
or O
partial O
Alteration O
of O
it O
. O

This O
Observation O
being O
considered O
, O
it O
will O
undeniably O
appear O
, O
that O
, O
in O
framing O
the O
late O
Stamp O
Act O
, O
the O
Commons B-Organization
acted O
in O
the O
Character O
of O
Representative O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
. O

They O
assumed O
it O
as O
the O
Principle O
of O
that O
Measure O
, O
and O
the O
Propriety O
of O
it O
must O
therefore O
stand O
, O
or O
fall O
, O
as O
the O
Principle O
is O
true O
, O
or O
false O
: O
For O
the O
Preamble O
sets O
forth O
, O
That O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great I-Organization
Britain I-Organization
had O
resolved O
to O
Give O
and O
Grant O
the O
several O
Rates O
and O
Duties O
imposed O
by O
the O
Act O
; O
but O
what O
Right O
had O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great I-Organization
Britain I-Organization
to O
be O
thus O
munificent O
at O
the O
Expence O
of O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
America I-Organization
? O

— O
To O
give O
Property O
, O
not O
belonging O
to O
the O
Giver O
, O
and O
without O
the O
Consent O
of O
the O
Owner O
, O
is O
such O
evident O
and O
flagrant O
Injustice O
, O
in O
ordinary O
Cases O
, O
that O
few O
are O
hardy O
enough O
to O
avow O
it O
; O
and O
therefore O
, O
when O
it O
really O
happens O
, O
the O
Fact O
is O
disguised O
and O
varnished O
over O
by O
the O
most O
plausible O
Pretences O
the O
Ingenuity O
of O
the O
Giver O
can O
suggest O
. O

— O
But O
it O
is O
alledged O
that O
there O
is O
a O
Virtual O
, O
or O
implied O
Representation O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
springing O
out O
of O
the O
Constitution O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Government I-Organization
: O
And O
it O
must O
be O
confessed O
on O
all O
Hands O
, O
that O
, O
as O
the O
Representation O
is O
not O
actual O
, O
it O
is O
virtual O
, O
or O
it O
doth O
not O
exist O
at O
all O
; O
for O
no O
third O
Kind O
of O
Representation O
can O
be O
imagined O
. O

The O
Colonies B-Organization
claim O
the O
Privilege O
, O
which O
is O
common O
to O
all O
British O
Subjects O
, O
of O
being O
taxed O
only O
with O
their O
own O
Consent O
given O
by O
their O
Representatives B-Organization
, O
and O
all O
the O
Advocates O
for O
the O
Stamp O
Act O
admit O
this O
Claim O
. O

Whether O
, O
therefore O
, O
upon O
the O
whole O
Matter O
, O
the O
Imposition O
of O
the O
Stamp O
Duties O
is O
a O
proper O
Exercise O
of O
Constitutional O
Authority O
, O
or O
not O
, O
depends O
upon O
the O
single O
Question O
, O
Whether O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great I-Organization
Britain I-Organization
are O
virtually O
the O
Representatives O
of O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
America I-Organization
, O
or O
not O
. O

The O
Advocates O
for O
the O
Stamp O
Act O
admit O
, O
in O
express O
Terms O
, O
that O
“ O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
do O
not O
chuse O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
” O
but O
They O
assert O
that O
“ O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
virtually O
represented O
in O
the O
same O
Manner O
with O
the O
NonElectors O
resident O
in O
Great B-Location
Britain I-Location
. O
” O

How O
have O
They O
proved O
this O
Position O
? O

Where O
have O
They O
defined O
, O
or O
precisely O
explained O
what O
They O
mean O
by O
the O
Expression O
, O
Virtual O
Representation O
? O

As O
it O
is O
the O
very O
Hinge O
upon O
which O
the O
Rectitude O
of O
the O
Taxation O
turns O
, O
something O
more O
satisfactory O
than O
mere O
Assertion O
, O
more O
solid O
than O
a O
Form O
of O
Expression O
, O
is O
necessary O
; O
for O
, O
how O
can O
it O
be O
seriously O
expected O
, O
that O
Men O
, O
who O
think O
Themselves O
injuriously O
affected O
in O
their O
Properties O
and O
Privileges O
, O
will O
be O
convinced O
and O
reconciled O
by O
a O
fanciful O
Phrase O
, O
the O
Meaning O
of O
which O
can O
’ O
t O
be O
precisely O
ascertained O
by O
those O
who O
use O
it O
, O
or O
properly O
applied O
to O
the O
Purpose O
for O
which O
it O
hath O
been O
advanced O
. O

They O
argue O
, O
that O
“ O
the O
Right O
of O
Election O
being O
annexed O
to O
certain O
Species O
of O
Property O
, O
to O
Franchises O
, O
and O
Inhabitancy O
in O
some O
particular O
Places O
, O
a O
very O
small O
Part O
of O
the O
Land O
, O
the O
Property O
, O
and O
the O
People O
of O
England B-Location
is O
comprehended O
in O
those O
Descriptions O
. O

All O
Landed O
Property O
, O
not O
Freehold O
, O
and O
all O
Monied O
Property O
, O
are O
excluded O
. O

The O
Merchants O
of O
London B-Location
, O
the O
Proprietors O
of O
the O
Public O
Funds O
, O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
Leeds B-Location
, O
Halifax B-Location
, O
Birmingham B-Location
, O
and O
Manchester B-Location
, O
and O
that O
great O
Corporation B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
East-India I-Organization
Company I-Organization
, O
None O
of O
Them O
chuse O
their O
Representatives O
, O
and O
yet O
are O
They O
all O
represented O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
and O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
being O
exactly O
in O
their O
Situation O
, O
are O
represented O
in O
the O
same O
Manner O
. O
” O

Now O
, O
this O
Argument O
, O
which O
is O
all O
that O
their O
Invention O
hath O
been O
able O
to O
supply O
, O
is O
totally O
defective O
; O
for O
, O
it O
consists O
of O
Facts O
not O
true O
, O
and O
of O
Conclusions O
inadmissible O
. O

It O
is O
so O
far O
from O
being O
true O
, O
that O
all O
the O
Persons O
enumerated O
under O
the O
Character O
of O
Non-Electors O
, O
are O
in O
that O
Predicament O
, O
that O
it O
is O
indubitably O
certain O
there O
is O
no O
Species O
of O
Property O
, O
landed O
, O
or O
monied O
, O
which O
is O
not O
possessed O
by O
very O
many O
of O
the O
British O
Electors O
. O

I O
shall O
undertake O
to O
disprove O
the O
supposed O
Similarity O
of O
Situation O
, O
whence O
the O
same O
Kind O
of O
Representation O
is O
deduced O
of O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
and O
of O
the O
British O
Non-Electors O
; O
and O
, O
if O
I O
succeed O
, O
the O
Notion O
of O
a O
virtual O
Representation O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
must O
fail O
, O
which O
, O
in O
Truth O
, O
is O
a O
mere O
Cob-web O
, O
spread O
to O
catch O
the O
unwary O
, O
and O
intangle O
the O
weak O
. O

I O
would O
be O
understood O
. O

I O
am O
upon O
a O
Question O
of O
Propriety O
, O
not O
of O
Power O
; O
and O
, O
though O
some O
may O
be O
inclined O
to O
think O
it O
is O
to O
little O
Purpose O
to O
discuss O
the O
one O
, O
when O
the O
other O
is O
irresistible O
, O
yet O
are O
They O
different O
Considerations O
; O
and O
, O
at O
the O
same O
Time O
that O
I O
invalidate O
the O
Claim O
upon O
which O
it O
is O
founded O
, O
I O
may O
very O
consistently O
recommend O
a O
Submission O
to O
the O
Law O
, O
whilst O
it O
endures O
. O

I O
shall O
say O
Nothing O
of O
the O
Use O
I O
intend O
by O
the O
Discussion O
; O
for O
, O
if O
it O
should O
not O
be O
perceived O
by O
the O
Sequel O
, O
there O
is O
no O
Use O
in O
it O
, O
and O
, O
if O
it O
should O
appear O
then O
, O
it O
need O
not O
be O
premised O
. O

Lessees O
for O
Years O
, O
Copyholders O
, O
Proprietors O
of O
the O
Public O
Funds O
, O
Inhabitants O
of O
Birmingham B-Location
, O
Leeds B-Location
, O
Halifax B-Location
, O
and O
Manchester B-Organization
, O
Merchants O
of O
the O
City O
of O
London B-Location
, O
or O
Members O
of O
the O
Corporation B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
East-India I-Organization
Company I-Organization
, O
are O
, O
as O
such O
, O
under O
no O
personal O
Incapacity O
to O
be O
Electors O
; O
for O
they O
may O
acquire O
the O
Right O
of O
Election O
, O
and O
there O
are O
actually O
not O
only O
a O
considerable O
Number O
of O
Electors O
in O
each O
of O
the O
Classes O
of O
Lessees O
for O
Years O
, O
& O
c O
. O
but O
in O
many O
of O
them O
, O
if O
not O
all O
, O
even O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
. O

The O
Interests O
therefore O
of O
the O
Non-Electors O
, O
the O
Electors O
, O
and O
the O
Representatives B-Organization
, O
are O
individually O
the O
same O
; O
to O
say O
nothing O
of O
the O
Connection O
among O
Neighbours O
, O
Friends O
, O
and O
Relations O
. O

The O
Security O
of O
the O
NonElectors O
against O
Oppression O
, O
is O
, O
that O
their O
Oppression O
will O
fall O
also O
upon O
the O
Electors O
and O
the O
Representatives B-Organization
. O

The O
one O
can O
’ O
t O
be O
injured O
, O
and O
the O
other O
indemnified O
. O

Further O
, O
if O
the O
Non-Electors O
should O
not O
be O
taxed O
by O
the O
British B-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
, O
They O
would O
not O
be O
taxed O
at O
all O
; O
and O
it O
would O
be O
iniquitous O
, O
as O
well O
as O
a O
Solecism O
, O
in O
the O
political O
System O
, O
that O
They O
should O
partake O
of O
all O
the O
Benefits O
resulting O
from O
the O
Imposition O
, O
and O
Application O
of O
Taxes O
, O
and O
derive O
an O
Immunity O
from O
the O
Circumstance O
of O
not O
being O
qualified O
to O
vote O
. O

Under O
this O
Constitution O
then O
, O
a O
double O
or O
virtual O
Representation O
may O
be O
reasonably O
supposed O
. O

— O
The O
Electors O
, O
who O
are O
inseparably O
connected O
in O
their O
Interests O
with O
the O
Non-Electors O
, O
may O
be O
justly O
deemed O
to O
be O
the O
Representatives O
of O
the O
Non-Electors O
, O
at O
the O
same O
Time O
They O
exercise O
their O
personal O
Privilege O
in O
their O
Right O
of O
Election O
, O
and O
the O
Members O
chosen O
, O
therefore O
, O
the O
Representatives O
of O
both O
. O

This O
is O
the O
only O
rational O
Explanation O
of O
the O
Expression O
, O
virtual O
Representation O
. O

None O
has O
been O
advanced O
by O
the O
Assertors O
of O
it O
, O
and O
their O
Meaning O
can O
only O
be O
inferred O
from O
the O
Instances O
, O
by O
which O
They O
endeavour O
to O
elucidate O
it O
, O
and O
no O
other O
Meaning O
can O
be O
stated O
, O
to O
which O
the O
Instances O
apply O
. O

It O
is O
an O
essential O
Principle O
of O
the O
English O
Constitution O
, O
that O
the O
Subject O
shall O
not O
be O
taxed O
without O
his O
Consent O
, O
which O
hath O
not O
been O
introduced O
by O
any O
particular O
Law O
, O
but O
necessarily O
results O
from O
the O
Nature O
of O
that O
mixed O
Government O
; O
for O
, O
without O
it O
, O
the O
Order O
of O
Democracy O
could O
not O
exist O
. O

Parliaments O
were O
not O
formerly O
so O
regular O
in O
Point O
of O
Form O
as O
they O
now O
are O
.1 O
Even O
the O
Number O
of O
Knights O
for O
each O
Shire O
were O
not O
ascertained O
. O

The O
first O
Writs O
now O
extant O
for O
their O
Choice O
, O
are O
22d O
Edward B-Person
I I-Person
, O
by O
which O
, O
Two O
, O
as O
at O
this O
Day O
, O
were O
directed O
to O
be O
chosen O
for O
each O
County O
; O
but O
the O
King B-Person
not O
being O
satisfied O
with O
that O
Number O
, O
other O
Writs O
were O
issued O
for O
chusing O
Two O
more O
. O

This O
discretionary O
Power O
being O
thought O
inconvenient O
, O
was O
afterwards O
restrained O
by O
the O
Statutes O
of O
Richard B-Person
II I-Person
, O
Henry B-Person
IV I-Person
, O
and O
subsequent O
Acts O
. O

In O
earlier O
Times O
there O
was O
more O
Simplicity O
in O
the O
Rules O
of O
Government O
, O
and O
Men O
were O
more O
solicitous O
about O
the O
Essentials O
, O
than O
the O
Forms O
of O
it O
. O

When O
the O
Consent O
of O
those O
who O
were O
to O
perform O
, O
or O
pay O
any O
Thing O
extra-feudal O
, O
was O
fairly O
applied O
for O
and O
obtained O
, O
the O
Manner O
was O
little O
regarded O
; O
but O
, O
as O
the O
People O
had O
reason O
to O
be O
jealous O
of O
Designs O
to O
impose O
Contributions O
upon O
Them O
without O
their O
Consent O
, O
it O
was O
thought O
expedient O
to O
have O
Formalities O
regulated O
, O
and O
fixed O
, O
to O
prevent O
this O
Injury O
to O
their O
Rights O
, O
not O
to O
destroy O
a O
Principle O
, O
without O
which O
, O
They O
could O
not O
be O
said O
to O
have O
any O
Rights O
at O
all O
. O

Before O
the O
Introduction O
of O
those O
Formalities O
, O
which O
were O
framed O
with O
a O
View O
to O
restrain O
the O
Excursions O
of O
Power O
, O
and O
to O
secure O
the O
Privileges O
of O
the O
Subject O
, O
as O
the O
Mode O
of O
Proceeding O
was O
more O
simple O
, O
so O
perhaps O
this O
Foundation O
of O
Consent O
was O
more O
visible O
than O
it O
is O
at O
present O
, O
wherefore O
it O
may O
be O
of O
Use O
to O
adduce O
some O
Instances O
, O
which O
directly O
point O
out O
this O
necessary O
and O
essential O
Principle O
of O
British O
Liberty O
. O

The O
Lords B-Organization
and O
Commons B-Organization
have O
separately O
given O
Aids O
and O
Subsidies O
to O
the O
Crown B-Organization
. O

In O
13th O
Edward B-Person
III I-Person
, O
the O
Lords B-Organization
granted O
the O
Tenth O
of O
all O
the O
Corn O
, O
& O
c O
. O
growing O
upon O
their O
Demesnes O
, O
the O
Commons B-Organization
then O
granting O
Nothing O
, O
nor O
concerning O
Themselves O
with O
what O
the O
Lords B-Organization
thought O
fit O
to O
grant O
out O
of O
their O
own O
Estates O
. O

— O
At O
other O
Times O
, O
the O
Knights B-Organization
of I-Organization
Shires I-Organization
, O
separating O
from O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
Commons B-Organization
, O
and O
joining O
with O
the O
Lords B-Organization
, O
have O
granted O
a O
Subsidy O
, O
and O
the O
Representatives O
of O
Cities O
and O
Boroughs O
have O
likewise O
granted O
Subsidies O
to O
the O
Crown B-Organization
separately O
, O
as O
appears O
by O
a O
Writ O
in O
24th O
Edward B-Person
I I-Person
, O
which O
runs O
in O
these O
Words O
: O
Rex O
, O
& O
c O
. O

— O
Cum O
Comites B-Organization
, O
Barones B-Organization
, O
Milites B-Organization
Nobis I-Organization
, O
& O
c O
. O
fecerunt O
undecimam O
de O
omnibus O
Bonis O
suis O
mobilibus O
, O
et O
Cives O
et O
Burgenses O
, O
& O
c O
. O
septimam O
de O
omnibus O
Bonis O
suis O
mobilibus O
, O
& O
c O
. O

nobis O
curialiter O
concesserint O
, O
& O
c O
. O

— O
When O
an O
Affair O
happened O
, O
which O
affected O
only O
some O
Individuals O
, O
and O
called O
for O
an O
Aid O
to O
the O
Crown B-Organization
, O
it O
was O
common O
for O
those O
Individuals O
alone O
to O
be O
summoned O
; O
to O
which O
Purpose O
several O
Writs O
arc O
extant O
. O

In O
35th O
Edward B-Person
III I-Person
, O
there O
is O
a O
Writ O
( O
which O
Dugdale B-Person
has O
printed O
in O
his O
Collection O
of O
Writs O
of O
Summons O
to O
Parliament B-Organization
) O
directed O
to O
the O
Earl B-Person
of I-Person
Northampton I-Person
, O
which O
, O
after O
reciting O
the O
Confusion O
the O
Affairs O
of O
Ireland B-Organization
were O
in O
, O
and O
that O
he O
, O
and O
some O
other O
English O
Lords O
had O
Possessions O
in O
that O
Kingdom B-Location
, O
and O
were O
therefore O
more O
particularly O
obliged O
to O
the O
Defence O
of O
it O
, O
follows O
in O
these O
Words O
: O
Volumus O
Vobiscum O
, O
et O
cum O
aliis O
de O
eodem O
Regno B-Organization
( O
Angliæ O
scilicet O
) O
Terras O
in O
dictâ O
Terrâ O
habentibus O
Colloquium O
habere O
, O
& O
c O
. O

But O
, O
that O
the O
Reader O
may O
perceive O
how O
strictly O
the O
Principle O
of O
no O
Persons O
being O
Taxed O
without O
their O
Consent O
, O
hath O
been O
regarded O
, O
it O
is O
proper O
to O
take O
Notice O
, O
that O
, O
upon O
the O
same O
Occasion O
, O
Writs O
were O
likewise O
directed O
even O
to O
Women O
, O
who O
were O
Proprietors O
of O
Land O
in O
Ireland B-Location
, O
to O
send O
their O
Deputies O
to O
consult O
, O
and O
consent O
to O
what O
should O
be O
judged O
necessary O
to O
be O
done O
on O
the O
Occasion O
; O
e O
. O
g O
. O

Rex O
, O
& O
c O
. O

— O
Mariæ O
, O
& O
c O
. O

Salutem O
, O
& O
c O
. O

Vobis O
, O
& O
c O
. O

Mandamus O
quod O
aliquem O
, O
vel O
aliquos O
de O
quibus O
confidatis O
apud O
Westmon O
. O

mittatis O
ad O
loquendum O
nobiscum O
super O
dictis O
Negotiis O
, O
et O
ad O
faciendum O
et O
consentiendum O
Nomine O
vestro O
, O
super O
hoc O
quod O
ibidem O
ordinari O
contigerit O
. O

A O
Reflection O
naturally O
arises O
from O
the O
Instances O
cited—When O
, O
on O
a O
particular O
Occasion O
, O
some O
Individuals O
only O
were O
to O
be O
taxed O
, O
and O
not O
the O
whole O
Community O
, O
their O
Consent O
only O
was O
called O
for O
, O
and O
in O
the O
last O
Instance O
it O
appears O
, O
that O
they O
, O
who O
upon O
an O
Occasion O
of O
a O
general O
Tax O
, O
would O
have O
been O
bound O
by O
the O
Consent O
of O
their O
virtual O
Representatives O
( O
for O
in O
that O
Case O
they O
would O
have O
had O
no O
actual O
Representatives O
) O
were O
in O
an O
Affair O
calling O
for O
a O
particular O
Aid O
from O
them O
, O
separate O
from O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
Community O
, O
required O
to O
send O
their O
particular O
Deputies O
. O

But O
how O
different O
would O
be O
the O
Principle O
of O
a O
Statute O
, O
imposing O
Duties O
without O
their O
Consent O
who O
are O
to O
pay O
them O
, O
upon O
the O
Authority O
of O
their O
Gift O
, O
who O
should O
undertake O
to O
give O
, O
what O
doth O
not O
belong O
to O
them O
. O

That O
great O
King B-Person
, I-Person
Edward I-Person
I I-Person
, O
inserted O
in O
his O
Writs O
of O
Summons O
, O
as O
a O
first O
Principle O
of O
Law O
, O
that O
quod O
omnes O
tangat O
ab O
omnibus O
approbetur O
, O
which O
by O
no O
Torture O
can O
be O
made O
to O
signify O
that O
their O
Approbation O
or O
Consent O
only O
is O
to O
be O
required O
in O
the O
Imposition O
of O
a O
Tax O
, O
who O
are O
to O
pay O
no O
Part O
of O
it O
. O

The O
Situation O
of O
the O
Non-Electors O
in O
England B-Location
—their O
Capacity O
to O
become O
Electors—their O
inseparable O
Connection O
with O
those O
who O
are O
Electors O
, O
and O
their O
Representatives—their O
Security O
against O
Oppression O
resulting O
from O
this O
Connection O
, O
and O
the O
Necessity O
of O
imagining O
a O
double O
or O
virtual O
Representation O
, O
to O
avoid O
Iniquity O
and O
Absurdity O
, O
have O
been O
explained—The O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
are O
, O
as O
such O
, O
incapable O
of O
being O
Electors O
, O
the O
Privilege O
of O
Election O
being O
exerciseable O
only O
in O
Person O
, O
and O
therefore O
if O
every O
Inhabitant O
of O
America B-Location
had O
the O
requisite O
Freehold O
, O
not O
one O
could O
vote O
, O
but O
upon O
the O
Supposition O
of O
his O
ceasing O
to O
be O
an O
Inhabitant O
of O
America B-Location
, O
and O
becoming O
a O
Resident O
in O
Great-Britain B-Location
, O
a O
Supposition O
which O
would O
be O
impertinent O
, O
because O
it O
shifts O
the O
Question—Should O
the O
Colonies B-Location
not O
be O
taxed O
by O
Parliamentary O
Impositions O
, O
their O
respective O
Legislatures O
have O
a O
regular O
, O
adequate O
, O
and O
constitutional O
Authority O
to O
Tax O
them O
, O
and O
therefore O
there O
would O
not O
necessarily O
be O
an O
iniquitous O
and O
absurd O
Exemption O
, O
from O
their O
not O
being O
represented O
by O
the O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
. O

There O
is O
not O
that O
intimate O
and O
inseparable O
Relation O
between O
the O
Electors O
of O
Great-Britain B-Location
and O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
, O
which O
must O
inevitably O
involve O
both O
in O
the O
same O
Taxation O
; O
on O
the O
contrary O
, O
not O
a O
single O
actual O
Elector O
in O
England B-Location
, O
might O
be O
immediately O
affected O
by O
a O
Taxation O
in O
America B-Location
, O
imposed O
by O
a O
Statute O
which O
would O
have O
a O
general O
Operation O
and O
Effect O
, O
upon O
the O
Properties O
of O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
. O

The O
latter O
might O
be O
oppressed O
in O
a O
Thousand O
Shapes O
, O
without O
any O
Sympathy O
, O
or O
exciting O
any O
Alarm O
in O
the O
former O
. O

Moreover O
, O
even O
Acts O
, O
oppressive O
and O
injurious O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
in O
an O
extreme O
Degree O
, O
might O
become O
popular O
in O
England B-Location
, O
from O
the O
Promise O
or O
Expectation O
, O
that O
the O
very O
Measures O
which O
depressed O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
would O
give O
Ease O
to O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
GreatBritain B-Location
. O

It O
is O
indeed O
true O
, O
that O
the O
Interests O
of O
England B-Organization
and O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
allied O
, O
and O
an O
Injury O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
produced O
into O
all O
it O
’ O
s O
Consequences O
, O
will O
eventually O
affect O
the O
Mother B-Organization
Country I-Organization
, O
yet O
these O
Consequences O
being O
generally O
remote O
, O
are O
not O
at O
once O
foreseen O
; O
they O
do O
not O
immediately O
alarm O
the O
Fears O
, O
and O
engage O
the O
Passions O
of O
the O
English O
Electors O
, O
the O
Connection O
between O
a O
Freeholder O
of O
Great B-Location
Britain I-Location
, O
and O
a O
British O
American O
being O
deducible O
only O
through O
a O
Train O
of O
Reasoning O
, O
which O
few O
will O
take O
the O
Trouble O
, O
or O
can O
have O
an O
Opportunity O
, O
if O
they O
have O
Capacity O
, O
to O
investigate O
; O
wherefore O
the O
Relation O
between O
the O
British-Americans O
, O
and O
the O
English O
Electors O
, O
is O
a O
Knot O
too O
infirm O
to O
be O
relied O
on O
as O
a O
competent O
Security O
, O
especially O
against O
the O
Force O
of O
a O
present O
, O
counteracting O
Expectation O
of O
Relief O
. O

If O
it O
would O
have O
been O
a O
just O
Conclusion O
, O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
being O
exactly O
in O
the O
same O
Situation O
with O
the O
Non-Electors O
of O
England B-Location
, O
are O
therefore O
represented O
in O
the O
same O
Manner O
, O
it O
ought O
to O
be O
allowed O
, O
that O
the O
Reasoning O
is O
solid O
, O
which O
, O
after O
having O
evinced O
a O
total O
Dissimilarity O
of O
Situation O
, O
infers O
that O
their O
Representation O
is O
different O
. O

If O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great-Britain I-Organization
have O
no O
Right O
by O
the O
Constitution O
, O
to O
GIVE O
AND O
GRANT O
Property O
not O
belonging O
to O
themselves O
or O
others O
, O
without O
their O
Consent O
actually O
or O
virtually O
given—If O
the O
Claim O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
not O
to O
be O
taxed O
without O
their O
Consent O
, O
signified O
by O
their O
Representatives B-Organization
, O
is O
well O
founded O
, O
if O
it O
appears O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
not O
actually O
represented O
by O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great-Britain I-Organization
, O
and O
that O
the O
Notion O
of O
a O
double O
or O
virtual O
Representation O
, O
doth O
not O
with O
any O
Propriety O
apply O
to O
the O
People O
of O
America B-Location
; O
then O
the O
Principle O
of O
the O
Stamp O
Act O
, O
must O
be O
given O
up O
as O
indefensible O
on O
the O
Point O
of O
Representation O
, O
and O
the O
Validity O
of O
it O
rested O
upon O
the O
Power O
which O
they O
who O
framed O
it O
, O
have O
to O
carry O
it O
into O
Execution O
. O

“ O
Should O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
devise O
a O
Tax O
, O
to O
be O
paid O
only O
by O
those O
of O
the O
People O
in O
Great-Britain B-Location
, O
who O
are O
neither O
Members O
of O
either O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
, O
nor O
their O
Electors O
, O
such O
an O
Act O
would O
be O
unjust O
and O
partial O
, O
” O
saith O
the O
Author O
of O
the O
Claim O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
& O
c O
. O
who O
yet O
allows O
that O
the O
“ O
Non-Electors O
would O
have O
a O
Security O
against O
the O
Weight O
of O
such O
a O
Tax O
, O
should O
it O
be O
imposed O
, O
which O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
have O
not O
, O
Viz O
. O

That O
the O
Members O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
and O
their O
Electors O
, O
must O
be O
relatively O
affected O
by O
it O
; O
but O
the O
industrious O
North-American O
, O
and O
the O
opulent O
West-Indian O
may O
have O
their O
Properties O
taxed O
, O
and O
no O
Individual O
in O
Great-Britain B-Location
participate O
with O
them O
in O
the O
Burden O
: O
On O
the O
contrary O
, O
the O
Members O
of O
Parliament O
would O
make O
their O
Court O
to O
their O
Constituents O
most O
effectually O
, O
by O
multiplying O
Taxes O
upon O
the O
Subjects O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
. O
” O

Is O
it O
not O
amazing O
that O
the O
above O
Author O
, O
with O
these O
Sentiments O
, O
should O
undertake O
the O
Defence O
of O
the O
Stamp O
Duties O
, O
which O
, O
by O
his O
own O
Concession O
, O
appear O
to O
be O
more O
unjust O
, O
and O
more O
partial O
than O
the O
Tax O
he O
supposes O
, O
and O
upon O
which O
he O
bestows O
, O
very O
properly O
, O
the O
Epithets O
of O
unjust O
and O
partial O
? O

— O
— O
Diluit O
Helleborum O
, O
certô O
compescere O
Punctô O
Nescius O
Examen O
. O

But O
it O
has O
been O
objected O
, O
that O
if O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
America B-Location
, O
because O
represented O
in O
their O
respective O
Assemblies B-Organization
, O
are O
therefore O
exempted O
from O
a O
Parliamentary O
Tax O
, O
then O
the O
Citizens O
of O
London B-Location
, O
who O
are O
represented O
in O
their O
Common B-Organization
Council I-Organization
, O
may O
plead O
the O
same O
Immunity O
. O

If O
it O
were O
not O
for O
the O
Authority O
upon O
which O
this O
Objection O
is O
urged O
it O
might O
be O
safely O
passed O
over O
without O
a O
particular O
Answer O
; O
but O
since O
it O
hath O
been O
introduced O
with O
an O
Appearance O
of O
Reliance O
, O
and O
the O
Opinion O
which O
it O
retails O
, O
is O
said O
to O
have O
been O
delivered O
with O
great O
Gravity O
, O
and O
pronounced O
with O
decisive O
Confidence O
, O
I O
would O
not O
be O
so O
wanting O
in O
Respect O
to O
an O
eminent O
Character O
, O
as O
to O
neglect O
the O
Ceremony O
of O
a O
direct O
Refutation O
. O

But O
I O
must O
observe O
that O
, O
when O
the O
Opinion O
of O
a O
Lawyer O
is O
taken O
in O
a O
Matter O
of O
private O
Concern O
, O
in O
which O
he O
is O
under O
no O
Bias O
to O
deceive O
, O
a O
concise O
Declaration O
of O
it O
may O
generally O
suffice O
; O
he O
who O
applies O
for O
it O
being O
generally O
obliged O
to O
depend O
upon O
his O
Council B-Organization
’ O
s O
Character O
of O
Integrity O
and O
Knowledge O
, O
not O
only O
because O
the O
Expence O
of O
a O
methodical O
and O
minute O
Discussion O
would O
be O
too O
Burthensome O
, O
but O
because O
the O
Force O
of O
legal O
Reasoning O
is O
not O
generally O
understood O
. O

But O
in O
a O
Question O
of O
Public O
Concernment O
, O
the O
Opinion O
of O
no O
Court O
Lawyer O
, O
however O
respectable O
for O
his O
Candour O
and O
Abilities O
, O
ought O
to O
weigh O
more O
than O
the O
Reasons O
adduced O
in O
Support O
of O
it O
. O

They O
ought O
to O
be O
explained O
, O
they O
may O
be O
examined O
. O

Considering O
his O
Temptations O
, O
Credit O
ought O
to O
be O
cautiously O
and O
diffidently O
given O
, O
to O
his O
Assertion O
of O
what O
is O
his O
Opinion O
. O

— O
Considering O
the O
Consequence O
of O
a O
Decision O
, O
not O
to O
one O
Man O
only O
, O
but O
to O
Millions O
that O
exist O
and O
Myriads O
that O
may O
exist O
, O
and O
the O
exceeding O
Fallibility O
of O
legal O
Knowledge O
, O
nothing O
short O
of O
clear O
Conviction O
, O
after O
the O
fullest O
Explication O
of O
the O
Reasons O
of O
the O
Opinion O
, O
and O
the O
most O
accurate O
and O
intense O
Consideration O
of O
their O
Validity O
, O
can O
justify O
an O
Acquiescence O
under O
it O
. O

On O
the O
present O
Occasion O
, O
so O
immensely O
important O
, O
Nullius O
addictus O
jurare O
in O
Verba O
Magistri O
, O
I O
shall O
pin O
my O
Faith O
upon O
the O
Dictum O
of O
no O
Lawyer O
in O
the O
Universe O
, O
and O
when O
his O
ipse O
dixit O
is O
authoritatively O
urged O
, O
I O
shall O
be O
at O
no O
Pains O
to O
repress O
my O
Suspicions O
that O
his O
Reasons O
are O
concealed O
, O
because O
, O
if O
fairly O
produced O
and O
held O
up O
to O
the O
Light O
, O
many O
Flaws O
in O
them O
would O
be O
discovered O
by O
a O
careful O
Examiner O
. O

I O
have O
lived O
long O
enough O
to O
remember O
many O
Opinions O
of O
Court O
Lawyers O
upon O
American O
Affairs O
; O
they O
have O
been O
all O
strongly O
marked O
with O
the O
same O
Character O
; O
they O
have O
been O
generally O
very O
sententious O
, O
and O
the O
same O
Observation O
may O
be O
applied O
to O
them O
all—They O
have O
all O
declared O
that O
to O
be O
legal O
, O
which O
the O
Minister B-Person
for O
the O
Time O
being O
has O
deemed O
to O
be O
expedient O
. O

The O
Opinion O
given O
by O
a O
General O
of O
the O
Law O
in O
the O
late O
War O
on O
the O
Question O
, O
Whether O
Soldiers O
might O
be O
Quartered O
on O
Private O
Houses O
in O
America B-Location
, O
must O
be O
pretty O
generally O
remembered O
. O

The O
very O
learned O
Gentlemen O
has O
, O
it O
seems O
, O
declared O
that O
, O
“ O
upon O
mature O
Deliberation O
, O
he O
has O
formed O
his O
Opinion O
, O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
in O
their O
Nature O
, O
no O
more O
than O
common O
Corporations O
, O
and O
that O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
a O
Colony B-Location
are O
no O
more O
entitled O
to O
an O
Exemption O
from O
Parliamentary O
Taxations O
, O
because O
represented O
in O
an O
American B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
, O
than O
the O
Citizens O
of O
London B-Location
. O
” O

This O
Opinion O
may O
be O
incontestably O
just O
in O
the O
Judgment O
of O
that O
accomplished O
Politician O
, O
and O
elegant O
Writer O
, O
who O
chuses O
to O
distinguish O
himself O
by O
the O
Titles O
of O
late O
G—rn—r B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
J—rs—ys I-Organization
, O
of B-Organization
the I-Organization
M—ss—ch—s I-Organization
— I-Organization
ts I-Organization
B I-Organization
— I-Organization
, O
and B-Organization
of I-Organization
S—th I-Organization
C—r—l—a I-Organization
, O
and O
who O
does O
not O
chuse O
to O
be O
distinguish O
’ O
d O
by O
the O
Title O
of O
late O
Mâitre O
d O
’ O
Hotel O
of O
the O
late O
Sir B-Person
D—v—s I-Person
O I-Person
— I-Person
b—e I-Person
, O
or O
that O
exactly O
fitting O
, O
and O
characteristical O
Appellation O
conferred O
on O
him O
, O
by O
an O
incensed O
Culprit O
in O
an O
American O
Court O
of O
Star-Chamber O
, O
an O
Appellation O
rather O
adapted O
to O
signify O
those O
Powers O
, O
which O
are O
useful O
in O
Intrigue O
, O
and O
that O
lead O
to O
Promotion O
, O
than O
expressive O
of O
Respect O
and O
Dignity2 O
; O
but O
having O
considered O
the O
Subject O
in O
the O
best O
Manner O
my O
very O
slender O
and O
limited O
Capacity O
will O
allow O
, O
neither O
doth O
the O
Opinion O
of O
the O
one O
, O
nor O
the O
Approbation O
of O
it O
by O
the O
other O
, O
influence O
my O
Judgment O
. O

Let O
a O
great O
Man O
declare O
a O
Similitude O
, O
and O
he O
will O
soon O
find O
a O
Polonius O
to O
acknowledge O
, O
that O
, O
“ O
Yonder O
Cloud O
is O
, O
by O
the O
Mass O
, O
like O
a O
Camel O
indeed O
” O
— O
or O
, O
“ O
black O
like O
an O
Ouzle O
, O
” O
— O
or O
, O
“ O
very O
like O
a O
Whale O
. O
” O

The O
Objection O
having O
been O
Stated O
, O
the O
Answer O
is O
obvious O
and O
clear O
. O

The O
Colonies B-Organization
have O
a O
compleat O
and O
adequate O
Legislative O
Authority O
, O
and O
are O
not O
only O
represented O
in O
their O
Assemblies B-Organization
, O
but O
in O
no O
other O
Manner O
. O

The O
Power O
of O
making O
Bye-Laws O
vested O
in O
the O
common B-Organization
Council I-Organization
is O
inadequate O
and O
incompleat O
, O
being O
bounded O
by O
a O
few O
particular O
Subjects O
; O
and O
the O
Common B-Organization
Council I-Organization
are O
actually O
represented O
too O
, O
by O
having O
a O
Choice O
of O
Members O
to O
serve O
in O
Parliament B-Organization
. O

How O
then O
can O
the O
Reason O
of O
the O
Exemption O
from O
internal O
Parliamentary O
Taxations O
, O
claimed O
by O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
apply O
to O
the O
Citizens O
of O
London B-Location
? O

The O
Power O
described O
in O
the O
Provincial O
Charters O
is O
to O
make O
Laws O
, O
and O
in O
the O
Exercise O
of O
that O
Power O
, O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
bounded O
by O
no O
other O
Limitations O
than O
what O
result O
from O
their O
Subordination O
to O
, O
and O
Dependance O
upon O
Great-Britain B-Organization
. O

The O
Term O
Bye-Laws O
is O
as O
novel O
, O
and O
improper O
, O
when O
applied O
to O
the O
Assemblies B-Organization
, O
as O
the O
Expression O
Acts O
of O
Assembly B-Organization
would O
be O
, O
if O
applied O
to O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great-Britain I-Organization
, O
and O
it O
is O
as O
absurd O
and O
insensible O
, O
to O
call O
a O
Colony O
a O
common O
Corporation O
, O
because O
not O
an O
independant O
Kingdom O
, O
and O
the O
Powers O
of O
each O
to O
make O
Laws O
and O
Bye O
Laws O
, O
are O
limited O
, O
tho O
’ O
not O
comparable O
in O
their O
Extent O
, O
and O
the O
Variety O
of O
their O
Objects O
, O
as O
it O
would O
be O
to O
call O
Lake B-Location
Erie I-Location
, O
a O
Duck-puddle O
, O
because O
not O
the O
Atlantic B-Location
Ocean I-Location
. O

Should O
the O
Analogy O
between O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
and O
Corporations O
be O
even O
admitted O
for O
a O
Moment O
, O
in O
order O
to O
see O
what O
would O
be O
the O
Consequence O
of O
the O
Postulatum O
, O
it O
would O
only O
amount O
to O
this O
, O
The O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
vested O
with O
as O
compleat O
Authority O
to O
all O
Intents O
and O
Purposes O
to O
Tax O
themselves O
, O
as O
any O
English O
Corporation O
is O
to O
make O
a O
Bye-Law O
, O
in O
any O
imaginable O
Instance O
for O
any O
local O
Purpose O
whatever O
, O
and O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
doth O
not O
make O
Laws O
for O
Corporations O
upon O
Subjects O
, O
in O
every O
Respect O
proper O
for O
Bye-Laws O
. O

But O
I O
don O
’ O
t O
rest O
the O
Matter O
upon O
this O
, O
or O
any O
other O
Circumstance O
, O
however O
considerable O
, O
to O
prove O
the O
Impropriety O
of O
a O
Taxation O
by O
the O
British B-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
. O

I O
rely O
upon O
the O
Fact O
, O
that O
not O
one O
Inhabitant O
in O
any O
Colony B-Location
is O
, O
or O
can O
be O
actually O
or O
virtually O
represented O
by O
the O
British B-Organization
House I-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
, O
and O
therefore O
, O
that O
the O
Stamp O
Duties O
are O
severely O
imposed O
. O

But O
it O
has O
been O
alledged O
, O
that O
if O
the O
Right O
to O
Give O
and O
Grant O
the O
Property O
of O
the O
Colonies O
by O
an O
internal O
Taxation O
is O
denied O
to O
the O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
, O
the O
Subordination O
or O
Dependance O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
and O
the O
Superintendence O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
can O
’ O
t O
be O
consistently O
establish O
’ O
d O
— O
That O
any O
supposed O
Line O
of O
Distinction O
between O
the O
Two O
Cases O
, O
is O
but O
“ O
a O
whimsical O
Imagination O
, O
a O
chimerical O
Speculation O
against O
Fact O
and O
Experience O
. O
” O

— O
Now O
, O
under O
Favour O
, O
I O
conceive O
there O
is O
more O
Confidence O
, O
than O
Solidity O
in O
this O
Assertion O
, O
and O
it O
may O
be O
satisfactorily O
and O
easily O
proved O
, O
that O
the O
Subordination O
and O
Dependance O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
may O
be O
preserved O
, O
and O
the O
supreme O
Authority O
of O
the O
Mother-Country B-Organization
be O
firmly O
supported O
, O
and O
yet O
the O
Principle O
of O
Representation O
, O
and O
the O
Right O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
House I-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
flowing O
from O
it O
, O
to O
Give O
and O
Grant O
the O
Property O
of O
the O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
America I-Organization
, O
be O
denied O
. O

The O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
dependant O
upon O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
, O
and O
the O
supreme O
Authority O
vested O
in O
the O
King B-Organization
, O
Lords B-Organization
, O
and O
Commons B-Organization
, O
may O
justly O
be O
exercised O
to O
secure O
, O
or O
preserve O
their O
Dependance O
, O
whenever O
necessary O
for O
that O
Purpose O
. O

This O
Authority O
results O
from O
, O
and O
is O
implied O
in O
the O
Idea O
of O
the O
Relation O
subsisting O
between O
England B-Organization
and O
her O
Colonies B-Organization
; O
for O
, O
considering O
the O
Nature O
of O
human O
Affections O
, O
the O
Inferior O
is O
not O
to O
be O
trusted O
with O
providing O
Regulations O
to O
prevent O
his O
Rising O
to O
an O
Equality O
with O
his O
Superior O
. O

But O
, O
though O
the O
Right O
of O
the O
Superior O
to O
use O
the O
proper O
Means O
for O
preserving O
the O
Subordination O
of O
his O
Inferior O
is O
admitted O
, O
yet O
it O
does O
not O
necessarily O
follow O
, O
that O
he O
has O
a O
Right O
to O
seize O
the O
Property O
of O
his O
Inferior O
when O
he O
pleases O
, O
or O
to O
command O
him O
in O
every O
Thing O
, O
since O
, O
in O
the O
Degrees O
of O
it O
, O
there O
may O
very O
well O
exist O
a O
Dependance O
and O
Inferiority O
, O
without O
absolute O
Vassalage O
and O
Slavery O
. O

In O
what O
the O
Superior O
may O
rightfully O
controul O
, O
or O
compel O
, O
and O
in O
what O
the O
Inferior O
ought O
to O
be O
at O
Liberty O
to O
act O
without O
Controul O
or O
Compulsion O
, O
depends O
upon O
the O
Nature O
of O
the O
Dependance O
, O
and O
the O
Degree O
of O
the O
Subordination O
; O
and O
, O
these O
being O
ascertained O
, O
the O
Measure O
of O
Obedience O
, O
and O
Submission O
, O
and O
the O
Extent O
of O
the O
Authority O
and O
Superintendence O
will O
be O
settled O
. O

When O
Powers O
, O
compatible O
with O
the O
Relation O
between O
the O
Superior O
and O
Inferior O
, O
have O
, O
by O
express O
Compact O
, O
been O
granted O
to O
, O
and O
accepted O
by O
the O
latter O
, O
and O
have O
been O
, O
after O
that O
Compact O
, O
repeatedly O
recognized O
by O
the O
former—When O
They O
may O
be O
exercised O
effectually O
upon O
every O
Occasion O
without O
any O
Injury O
to O
that O
Relation O
, O
the O
Authority O
of O
the O
Superior O
can O
’ O
t O
properly O
interpose O
; O
for O
, O
by O
the O
Powers O
vested O
in O
the O
Inferior O
, O
is O
the O
Superior O
limited O
. O

By O
their O
Constitutions O
of O
Government O
, O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
impowered O
to O
impose O
internal O
Taxes O
. O

This O
Power O
is O
compatible O
with O
their O
Dependance O
, O
and O
hath O
been O
expressly O
recognized O
by O
British B-Organization
Ministers I-Organization
and O
the O
British B-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
, O
upon O
many O
Occasions O
; O
and O
it O
may O
be O
exercised O
effectually O
without O
striking O
at O
, O
or O
impeaching O
, O
in O
any O
Respect O
, O
the O
Superintendence O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
. O

May O
not O
then O
the O
Line O
be O
distinctly O
and O
justly O
drawn O
between O
such O
Acts O
as O
are O
necessary O
, O
or O
proper O
, O
for O
preserving O
or O
securing O
the O
Dependance O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
and O
such O
as O
are O
not O
necessary O
or O
proper O
for O
that O
very O
important O
Purpose O
? O

When O
the O
Powers O
were O
conferred O
upon O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
They O
were O
conferred O
too O
as O
Privileges O
and O
Immunities O
, O
and O
accepted O
as O
such O
; O
or O
, O
to O
speak O
more O
properly O
, O
the O
Privileges O
belonging O
necessarily O
to O
Them O
as O
British O
Subjects O
, O
were O
solemnly O
declared O
and O
confirmed O
by O
their O
Charters O
, O
and O
They O
who O
settled O
in O
America B-Location
under O
the O
Encouragement O
and O
Faith O
of O
these O
Charters O
, O
understood O
, O
not O
only O
that O
They O
might O
, O
but O
that O
it O
was O
their O
Right O
to O
exercise O
those O
Powers O
without O
Controul O
, O
or O
Prevention O
. O

In O
some O
of O
the O
Charters O
the O
Distinction O
is O
expressed O
, O
and O
the O
strongest O
Declarations O
made O
, O
and O
the O
most O
solemn O
Assurances O
given O
that O
the O
Settlers O
should O
not O
have O
their O
Property O
taxed O
without O
their O
own O
Consent O
by O
their O
Representatives B-Organization
, O
though O
their O
legislative O
Authority O
is O
limited O
at O
the O
same O
Time O
, O
by O
the O
Subordination O
implied O
in O
their O
Relation O
, O
and O
They O
are O
therefore O
restrained O
from O
making O
Acts O
of O
Assembly B-Organization
repugnant O
to O
the O
Laws O
of O
England B-Organization
, O
and O
, O
had O
the O
Distinction O
not O
been O
expressed O
, O
the O
Powers O
given O
would O
have O
implied O
it O
, O
for O
, O
if O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
may O
in O
any O
Case O
interpose O
, O
when O
the O
Authority O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
is O
adequate O
to O
the O
Occasion O
, O
and O
not O
limited O
by O
their O
Subordination O
to O
the O
Mother-Country B-Organization
, O
it O
may O
in O
every O
Case O
, O
which O
would O
make O
another O
Appellation O
more O
proper O
to O
describe O
their O
Condition O
, O
than O
the O
Name O
by O
which O
their O
Inhabitants O
have O
been O
usually O
called O
, O
and O
have O
Gloried O
in O
. O

Because O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
may O
, O
when O
the O
Relation O
between O
Great-Britain B-Organization
and O
her O
Colonies B-Organization
calls O
for O
an O
Exertion O
of O
her O
Superintendance O
, O
bind O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
by O
Statute O
, O
therefore O
a O
Parliamentary O
Interposition O
in O
every O
other O
Instance O
, O
is O
justifiable O
, O
is O
an O
Inference O
that O
may O
be O
denied O
. O

On O
some O
Emergencies O
, O
the O
King B-Organization
, O
by O
the O
Constitution O
, O
hath O
an O
absolute O
Power O
to O
provide O
for O
the O
Safety O
of O
the O
State B-Organization
, O
to O
take O
Care O
, O
like O
a O
Roman O
Dictator O
, O
ne O
quid O
Detrimenti O
capiat O
Respublica O
, O
and O
this O
Power O
is O
not O
specifically O
annexed O
to O
the O
Monarchy O
by O
any O
express O
Law O
; O
it O
necessarily O
results O
from O
the O
End O
and O
Nature O
of O
Government O
, O
but O
who O
would O
infer O
from O
this O
, O
that O
the O
King B-Organization
, O
in O
every O
Instance O
, O
or O
upon O
every O
Occasion O
, O
can O
, O
upon O
the O
Principles O
of O
the O
Constitution O
, O
exercise O
this O
supreme O
Power O
? O

The O
British B-Organization
Ministers I-Organization
have O
, O
in O
the O
most O
effectual O
Terms O
, O
at O
different O
Periods O
, O
from O
the O
Reign O
of O
Charles B-Person
II I-Person
, O
to O
that O
of O
the O
present O
King B-Person
, O
recognized O
this O
Distinction O
in O
their O
Requisitions O
, O
transmitted O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
to O
raise O
and O
levy O
Men O
and O
Money O
, O
by O
Acts O
of O
Assembly B-Organization
; O
and O
recently O
, O
in O
the O
Course O
of O
the O
last O
War O
, O
they O
were O
so O
far O
from O
thinking O
that O
it O
was O
proper O
for O
the O
British B-Organization
House I-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
to O
Give O
and O
Grant O
the O
Property O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
to O
support O
the O
military O
Operations O
in O
America B-Location
, O
upon O
which O
not O
only O
the O
immediate O
Protection O
of O
that O
Part O
of O
the O
British B-Location
Dominions I-Location
, O
but O
the O
most O
important O
Interests O
, O
perhaps O
the O
ultimate O
Preservation O
of O
Great B-Organization
Britain I-Organization
from O
Destruction O
, O
essentially O
depended O
; O
I O
say O
, O
on O
this O
great O
Occasion O
of O
the O
most O
important O
, O
and O
national O
Concernment O
, O
the O
British B-Organization
Ministers I-Organization
were O
so O
far O
from O
calling O
upon O
the O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
, O
in O
their O
peculiar O
Department O
, O
to O
Give O
and O
Grant O
Property O
, O
belonging O
neither O
to O
Themselves O
, O
nor O
their O
Constituents O
, O
that O
They O
directly O
applied O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
to O
tax O
Themselves O
, O
in O
Virtue O
of O
the O
Authority O
and O
Privilege O
conferred O
by O
their O
Charters O
, O
and O
promised O
to O
recommend O
it O
to O
the O
British B-Organization
Parliament I-Organization
to O
reimburse O
the O
Expence O
They O
should O
incur O
in O
providing O
for O
the O
general O
Service O
. O

— O
They O
made O
good O
their O
Promise O
; O
and O
, O
if O
all O
the O
Money O
raised O
in O
the O
Colonies B-Location
, O
by O
Acts O
of O
Assembly B-Organization
, O
in O
pursuance O
of O
the O
Requisitions O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Ministers I-Organization
, O
hath O
not O
been O
repaid O
by O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
a O
very O
considerable O
Part O
of O
it O
hath O
. O

Could O
They O
, O
who O
made O
the O
Requisitions O
I O
have O
mentioned O
, O
or O
the O
Assemblies O
that O
complied O
with O
them O
, O
intend O
, O
or O
imagine O
the O
Faith O
of O
the O
English B-Organization
Government I-Organization
was O
to O
be O
preserved O
by O
a O
Retribution O
, O
at O
one O
Time O
, O
of O
the O
Money O
disbursed O
at O
the O
Instance O
, O
and O
upon O
the O
Credit O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Ministry I-Organization
, O
enforced O
and O
supported O
by O
Royal O
Assurances O
, O
and O
by O
taking O
it O
back O
again O
at O
another O
Time O
? O

Is O
this O
Method O
of O
keeping O
the O
Faith O
of O
Government O
to O
be O
ranked O
among O
the O
“ O
Improvements O
which O
have O
been O
made O
beyond O
the O
Idea O
of O
former O
Administrations O
, O
concluded O
by O
Ministers B-Organization
ignorant O
of O
the O
Importance O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
, O
or O
who O
impotently O
neglected O
their O
Concerns O
, O
or O
were O
diverted O
by O
mean O
Pursuits O
, O
from O
attending O
to O
Them O
? O
” O

Is O
it O
absolutely O
certain O
, O
that O
there O
never O
can O
, O
at O
any O
future O
Period O
, O
arise O
a O
Crisis O
, O
in O
which O
the O
Exertion O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
may O
be O
necessary O
, O
or O
, O
if O
there O
should O
, O
that O
it O
will O
bring O
with O
it O
an O
Oblivion O
of O
all O
former O
Indirection O
? O

— O
But O
this O
is O
a O
Subject O
fitter O
for O
silent O
Meditation O
, O
than O
public O
Discussion O
. O

There O
was O
a O
Time O
when O
Measures O
of O
Prevention O
might O
have O
been O
taken O
by O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
. O

— O
There O
may O
be O
a O
Time O
when O
Redress O
may O
be O
obtained—Till O
then O
, O
Prudence O
, O
as O
well O
as O
Duty O
, O
requires O
Submission O
. O

It O
is O
presumed O
that O
it O
was O
a O
notable O
Service O
done O
by O
New-England B-Organization
, O
when O
the O
Militia O
of O
that O
Colony B-Organization
reduced O
Cape-Breton B-Location
, O
since O
it O
enabled O
the O
British B-Organization
Ministers I-Organization
to O
make O
a O
Peace O
less O
disadvantageous O
and O
inglorious O
than O
They O
otherwise O
must O
have O
been O
constrained O
to O
submit O
to O
, O
in O
the O
humble O
State O
to O
which O
they O
were O
then O
reduc O
’ O
d O
. O

— O
That O
the O
general O
Exertion O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
in I-Organization
North-America I-Organization
, O
during O
the O
last O
War O
, O
not O
only O
facilitated O
, O
but O
was O
indispensably O
requisite O
to O
the O
Success O
of O
those O
Operations O
by O
which O
so O
many O
glorious O
Conquests O
were O
atchieved O
, O
and O
that O
those O
Conquests O
have O
put O
it O
in O
the O
Power O
of O
the O
present O
illustrious O
Ministers B-Organization
to O
make O
a O
Peace O
upon O
Terms O
of O
so O
much O
Glory O
and O
Advantage O
, O
as O
to O
afford O
an O
inexhaustible O
Subject O
during O
their O
Administration O
, O
and O
the O
Triumph O
of O
Toryism O
, O
at O
least O
, O
for O
their O
ingenious O
Panegyrists O
to O
celebrate O
. O

An O
American O
, O
without O
justly O
incurring O
the O
Imputation O
of O
Ingratitude O
, O
may O
doubt O
, O
whether O
some O
other O
Motive O
, O
besides O
pure O
Generosity O
, O
did O
not O
prompt O
the O
British B-Organization
Nation I-Organization
to O
engage O
in O
the O
Defence O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
. O

— O
He O
may O
be O
induced O
to O
think O
that O
the O
Measures O
taken O
for O
the O
Protection O
of O
the O
Plantations B-Location
, O
were O
not O
only O
connected O
with O
the O
Interests O
, O
but O
even O
necessary O
to O
the O
Defence O
of O
Great-Britain B-Location
herself O
, O
because O
he O
may O
have O
Reason O
to O
imagine O
that O
Great-Britain B-Organization
could O
not O
long O
subsist O
as O
an O
independent O
Kingdom O
after O
the O
Loss O
of O
her O
Colonies B-Location
. O

— O
He O
may O
, O
without O
Arrogance O
, O
be O
inclined O
to O
claim O
some O
Merit O
from O
the O
Exertion O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
since O
it O
enabled O
Great-Britain B-Organization
ultimately O
to O
defend O
herself O
; O
I O
mean O
that O
Kind O
of O
Merit O
which O
arises O
from O
Benefits O
done O
to O
others O
, O
by O
the O
Operation O
of O
Measures O
taken O
for O
our O
own O
Sakes—a O
Merit O
most O
illustriously O
display O
’ O
d O
in O
the O
Generosity O
of O
Great-Britain B-Organization
, O
when O
, O
with O
their O
Co-operation O
, O
she O
protected O
the O
Colonies B-Location
to O
preserve O
herself O
. O

When O
an O
House O
is O
in O
Flames O
, O
and O
the O
next O
Neighbour O
is O
extremely O
active O
, O
and O
exerts O
his O
Endeavours O
to O
extinguish O
the O
Fire O
, O
which O
, O
if O
not O
conquered O
, O
would O
catch O
, O
and O
consume O
his O
own O
Dwelling O
, O
I O
don O
’ O
t O
say O
, O
that O
if O
the O
Owner O
of O
the O
House O
which O
had O
been O
in O
Flames O
, O
should O
, O
after O
the O
Fire O
subdued O
, O
complaisantly O
thank O
his O
Neighbour O
generally O
for O
his O
Services O
, O
he O
would O
be O
absurdly O
ceremonious O
; O
but O
, O
if O
the O
Assistant O
should O
afterwards O
boast O
of O
his O
great O
Generosity O
, O
and O
claim O
a O
Right O
to O
the O
Furniture O
of O
the O
House O
which O
he O
had O
assisted O
in O
Saving O
, O
upon O
the O
Merit O
of O
his O
Zeal O
and O
Activity O
, O
he O
would O
deserve O
to O
be O
put O
in O
Mind O
of O
the O
Motive O
of O
his O
Service O
. O

If O
the O
Advantages O
gained O
by O
the O
late O
most O
glorious O
and O
succesful O
War O
have O
been O
secured O
by O
an O
adequate O
Peace—If O
the O
Successes O
that O
attended O
the O
military O
Operations O
of O
the O
British O
Arms O
, O
were O
the O
Effect O
of O
the O
conjunct O
Efforts O
of O
the O
British B-Organization
Nation I-Organization
and O
her O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
roused O
by O
the O
Spirit O
, O
excited O
by O
the O
Virtue O
, O
animated O
by O
the O
Vigour O
, O
and O
conducted O
by O
the O
Wisdom O
of O
the O
ablest O
Minister O
that O
ever O
served O
his O
Country B-Organization
, O
has O
there O
been O
no O
Compensation O
received O
for O
the O
Charges O
of O
the O
War O
? O

Are O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
entitled O
to O
no O
Credit O
for O
it O
? O

When O
the O
Design O
is O
to O
oppress O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
with O
Taxes O
, O
or O
calumniate O
the O
late O
patriotic O
Minister B-Person
, O
the O
Expences O
of O
the O
War O
, O
and O
the O
Enormity O
of O
the O
national O
Debt O
are O
proclaimed O
: O
When O
the O
present O
all-accomplish O
’ O
d O
Administration B-Organization
is O
to O
be O
celebrated O
, O
then O
is O
the O
immense O
Value O
of O
the O
new O
Acquisitions O
display O
’ O
d O
in O
the O
brightest O
Colours O
, O
“ O
Acquisitions O
vast O
in O
Extent O
, O
richly O
productive O
of O
the O
valuable O
Commodities O
belonging O
to O
their O
several O
Climates O
. O

The O
Possession O
of O
those O
in O
North-America B-Location
, O
ensures O
the O
Safety O
of O
the O
other O
Colonies O
there O
, O
insomuch O
that O
our O
only O
dangerous O
Neighbours O
, O
the O
French O
, O
do O
not O
think O
the O
Pittance O
left O
worth O
retaining O
, O
having O
, O
by O
the O
Cession O
of O
Louisiana B-Location
to O
the O
Spaniards O
, O
avowedly O
given O
up O
for O
ever O
those O
great O
Objects O
, O
for O
which O
alone O
They O
began O
the O
War O
. O

— O
The O
ceded B-Location
Islands I-Location
are O
almost O
of O
equal O
Advantage O
, O
for O
protecting O
our O
own O
, O
and O
annoying O
the O
Settlements O
of O
the O
French O
and O
Spaniards O
, O
if O
They O
should O
be O
again O
our O
Enemies O
. O

— O
Part O
of O
Nova B-Location
Scotia I-Location
, O
since O
the O
Removal O
of O
the O
neutral O
French O
, O
hath O
been O
already O
settled O
by O
10,000 O
Inhabitants O
, O
within O
the O
Compass O
of O
Six O
or O
Seven O
Years O
, O
a O
Province O
lately O
considered O
as O
no O
more O
than O
a O
proper O
Situation O
for O
a O
Fortress O
, O
whose O
Garrison O
it O
could O
not O
subsist O
: O
Even O
Cape-Breton B-Location
, O
that O
barren O
Appendage O
to O
the O
Province B-Location
of I-Location
Nova I-Location
Scotia I-Location
, O
is O
known O
now O
to O
contain O
Treasures O
so O
worthy O
of O
Attention O
, O
as O
to O
be O
reserved O
to O
the O
Crown B-Organization
. O

The O
Mines O
there O
are O
not O
Veins O
; O
they O
are O
Mountains O
of O
Coal O
; O
vast O
Clifts O
of O
nothing O
else O
, O
stand O
open O
, O
and O
accessible O
; O
no O
Boring O
necessary O
to O
find O
it O
; O
no O
Pit O
necessary O
to O
come O
at O
it O
; O
no O
Fire-Engines O
requisite O
for O
carrying O
on O
the O
Works O
. O

This O
Island B-Location
, O
and O
all O
the O
neighbouring O
Shores O
in O
the O
Gulph O
of O
St O
. O

Laurence B-Location
, O
have O
another O
Fund O
of O
Wealth O
in O
their O
Fisheries O
. O

Canada B-Location
is O
already O
a O
very O
flourishing O
Colony O
, O
inhabited O
by O
90,000 O
People O
, O
and O
their O
Demand O
on O
Great-Britain B-Organization
for O
a O
Supply O
of O
Manufactures O
, O
must O
be O
immediately O
considerable O
. O

The O
Peltry O
will O
be O
another O
great O
Branch O
of O
Commerce O
. O

West-Florida B-Location
is O
surprizingly O
fertile O
, O
and O
luxuriantly O
productive O
in O
its O
natural O
State O
, O
of O
every O
Thing O
, O
and O
not O
only O
promising O
, O
but O
actually O
producing O
Wines O
and O
Silk O
, O
and O
Indigo O
, O
& O
c O
. O

& O
c O
. O
” O

Is O
no O
Part O
of O
this O
Description O
the O
Ebullition O
of O
an O
exuberant O
Fancy O
, O
and O
shall O
we O
not O
cast O
one O
Glance O
of O
Retrospection O
towards O
the O
Man O
, O
who O
, O
when O
his O
Country O
was O
despised O
, O
and O
insulted O
, O
and O
sunk O
into O
the O
most O
abject O
Condition O
of O
Despondence O
, O
by O
inspiring O
her O
Sons O
with O
that O
invincible O
Vigour O
of O
Patriotism O
, O
with O
which O
himself O
was O
animated O
, O
not O
only O
dispelled O
her O
Fears O
, O
secured O
her O
Safety O
, O
and O
retrieved O
her O
Honour O
, O
but O
Humbled O
her O
Enemies O
, O
and O
tore O
from O
them O
the O
Resources O
of O
their O
Strength O
, O
and O
the O
Supports O
of O
their O
Insolence O
? O

Are O
the O
Acquisitions O
of O
the O
War O
retained O
by O
the O
Peace O
, O
so O
inestimably O
valuable O
, O
and O
ought O
not O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
to O
have O
some O
Consideration O
that O
were O
instrumental O
in O
the O
Successes O
whence O
those O
Acquisitions O
flowed O
, O
and O
strained O
every O
Nerve O
in O
the O
general O
Service O
, O
to O
that O
Degree O
of O
Exertion O
, O
that O
without O
it O
, O
all O
the O
Power O
of O
Great-Britain B-Organization
, O
all O
the O
amazing O
Abilities O
of O
her O
Minister B-Person
, O
and O
all O
the O
Discipline O
, O
and O
unparallel O
’ O
d O
Bravery O
of O
her O
national O
Troops O
and O
Seamen O
, O
could O
not O
have O
availed O
beyond O
meer O
Defence O
, O
if O
happily O
so O
far O
? O

If O
the O
War O
was O
expensive O
beyond O
all O
former O
Example O
, O
so O
were O
the O
Successes O
of O
it O
beneficial O
. O

If O
the O
Expences O
attending O
the O
military O
Operations O
in O
America B-Location
, O
are O
justly O
to O
be O
charged O
to O
the O
sole O
Defence O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
, O
and O
no O
Part O
of O
it O
to O
the O
Security O
of O
Great-Britain B-Organization
, O
or O
to O
the O
Views O
of O
extending O
her O
Dominions B-Location
by O
Conquest O
, O
if O
all O
the O
Successes O
of O
the O
War O
have O
been O
atchieved O
by O
the O
national O
Arms O
of O
Great-Britain B-Organization
ALONE O
, O
without O
any O
Assistance O
, O
or O
Co-operation O
of O
the O
Plantations B-Organization
, O
still O
ought O
not O
the O
Claim O
against O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
in O
Equity O
, O
to O
be O
mitigated O
upon O
Reflection O
of O
the O
Advantages O
derived O
from O
Them O
, O
and O
of O
their O
Contribution O
to O
the O
national O
Revenue O
for O
a O
long O
Course O
of O
Years O
, O
during O
which O
, O
their O
Protection O
put O
the O
British B-Organization
Nation I-Organization
to O
very O
little O
, O
if O
any O
particular O
Expence O
? O

If O
moreover O
, O
Great-Britain B-Organization
hath O
an O
equitable O
Claim O
to O
the O
Contribution O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
it O
ought O
to O
be O
proportioned O
to O
their O
Circumstances O
, O
and O
They O
might O
, O
surely O
, O
be O
indulged O
with O
discharging O
it O
in O
the O
most O
easy O
, O
and O
satisfactory O
Manner O
to O
Themselves O
. O

If O
Ways O
and O
Means O
convenient O
, O
and O
conciliating O
would O
produce O
their O
Contribution O
, O
as O
well O
as O
oppressive O
and O
disgusting O
Exactions O
, O
it O
is O
neither O
consistent O
with O
Humanity O
or O
Policy O
, O
to O
pursue O
the O
latter—A O
Power O
may O
even O
exist O
without O
an O
actual O
Exercise O
of O
it O
, O
and O
it O
indicates O
as O
little O
good O
Sense O
as O
good O
Nature O
to O
exercise O
it O
, O
only O
that O
the O
Subjects O
of O
it O
may O
feel O
the O
Rod O
that O
Rules O
Them O
. O

Moderation O
may O
be O
observed O
, O
and O
Equity O
maintained O
, O
at O
the O
same O
Time O
that O
Superiority O
is O
asserted O
, O
and O
Authority O
vindicated O
, O
whatever O
the O
Apprehensions O
of O
Pusillanimity O
, O
or O
the O
Insolence O
of O
Usurpation O
may O
suggest O
. O

What O
is O
the O
annual O
Sum O
expected O
from O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
—what O
Proportion O
from O
each—how O
far O
do O
their O
Abilities O
extend O
? O

These O
Matters O
have O
been O
, O
without O
doubt O
, O
precisely O
ascertained O
, O
or O
easily O
may O
be O
, O
at O
a O
Time O
“ O
when O
the O
real O
, O
the O
substantial O
, O
the O
commercial O
Interests O
of O
Great-Britain B-Organization
, O
are O
preferred O
to O
every O
other O
Consideration O
, O
and O
it O
is O
so O
well O
known O
, O
that O
the O
Trade O
whence O
it O
’ O
s O
greatest O
Wealth O
is O
derived O
, O
and O
upon O
which O
it O
’ O
s O
maritime O
Power O
is O
principally O
founded O
, O
depends O
upon O
a O
wise O
and O
proper O
Use O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
, O
” O
which O
implies O
, O
at O
least O
, O
such O
an O
Understanding O
of O
their O
Circumstances O
, O
as O
must O
render O
it O
extremely O
easy O
, O
to O
form O
a O
reasonable O
Estimate O
of O
their O
comparative O
Wealth O
, O
and O
the O
Extent O
of O
their O
Abilities O
. O

The O
proportion O
of O
each O
Colony B-Organization
, O
being O
so O
easily O
ascertainable O
at O
this O
Period O
of O
uncommon O
Knowledge O
of O
their O
Affairs O
, O
why O
has O
the O
Course O
observed O
by O
former O
Ministers B-Organization
, O
when O
Supplies O
have O
been O
expected O
from O
America B-Organization
, O
been O
neglected O
by O
the O
present O
? O

Why O
was O
there O
not O
the O
usual O
Requisition O
communicated O
to O
the O
Provincial B-Organization
Assemblies I-Organization
, O
instead O
of O
exacting O
an O
uncertain O
and O
unequal O
Sum O
from O
each O
Colony O
, O
by O
a O
Law O
abruptly O
passed O
, O
without O
any O
previous O
Default O
of O
those O
who O
are O
affected O
by O
it O
? O

— O
I O
shall O
not O
call O
it O
a O
Law O
repugnant O
to O
their O
Genius O
, O
cancelling O
their O
Charters O
, O
infringing O
the O
most O
valuable O
Rights O
and O
Privileges O
of O
British O
Subjects O
, O
derogatory O
from O
the O
Faith O
and O
Honour O
of O
Government O
, O
unjust O
and O
cruel O
in O
it O
’ O
s O
Principles O
, O
rigorous O
and O
oppressive O
in O
the O
Means O
provided O
for O
it O
’ O
s O
Execution O
, O
and O
as O
pernicious O
in O
it O
’ O
s O
Consequences O
to O
the O
Mother B-Organization
Country I-Organization
, O
as O
injurious O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
in O
it O
’ O
s O
immediate O
Operation O
, O
but O
I O
may O
call O
it O
a O
rigorous O
and O
severe O
Law O
. O

It O
is O
in O
vain O
to O
attempt O
a O
Palliation O
of O
this O
useless O
Severity O
, O
( O
useless O
I O
mean O
to O
the O
Purpose O
of O
raising O
a O
Revenue O
) O
by O
fallaciously O
pretending O
that O
, O
as O
all O
the O
Colonies B-Location
were O
to O
be O
taxed O
, O
and O
the O
Authority O
of O
each O
is O
limited O
, O
the O
Interposition O
of O
the O
Parliament B-Organization
became O
necessary O
, O
since O
Nothing O
can O
be O
less O
disputable O
, O
than O
that O
each O
Colony B-Organization
hath O
a O
competent O
Authority O
to O
raise O
it O
’ O
s O
Proportion O
, O
and O
consequently O
nothing O
is O
more O
evident O
, O
than O
that O
all O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
might O
raise O
the O
whole O
. O

The O
Assertion3 O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
would O
have O
paid O
no O
Regard O
to O
any O
Requisitions O
, O
is O
rash O
and O
unauthoriz O
’ O
d O
, O
and O
had O
the O
Event O
actually O
happened O
, O
the O
Trouble O
and O
Loss O
of O
Time O
to O
the O
Ministers B-Organization
in O
making O
the O
Experiment O
, O
would O
not O
have O
been O
considerable O
or O
detrimental O
to O
the O
Nation B-Organization
, O
and O
after O
it O
’ O
s O
Failure O
, O
an O
Act O
of O
Parliament B-Organization
might O
still O
have O
been O
made O
to O
compel O
the O
Contribution O
, O
if O
the O
Power O
which O
hath O
been O
exercised O
is O
defensible O
upon O
the O
Principles O
of O
the O
British O
Constitution O
. O

A O
Measure O
so O
extreme O
, O
could O
hardly O
be O
at O
once O
pursued O
, O
because O
the O
Ministers B-Organization
did O
not O
know O
what O
to O
demand O
, O
who O
have O
made O
so O
many O
Regulations O
in O
regard O
to O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
“ O
founded O
upon O
Knowledge O
, O
formed O
with O
Judgment O
, O
and O
executed O
with O
Vigour O
. O
” O

Had O
the O
Requisitions O
been O
communicated O
, O
I O
make O
no O
Doubt O
but O
They O
would O
have O
been O
entertained O
with O
Respect O
, O
and O
productive O
of O
all O
the O
Effects O
that O
could O
reasonably O
have O
been O
expected O
from O
Them O
. O

A O
petty O
American B-Organization
Assembly I-Organization
would O
not O
, O
in O
Answer O
to O
such O
Requisitions O
, O
have O
impertinently O
recommended O
the O
Reduction O
of O
exorbitant O
Salaries O
, O
the O
Abatement O
of O
extravagant O
, O
and O
the O
Abolition O
of O
illegal O
Perquisites O
, O
the O
Extinction O
of O
useless O
Places O
, O
or O
the O
disbanding O
of O
undeserving O
, O
or O
ill O
deserving O
Pensioners O
, O
as O
a O
more O
proper O
and O
beneficial O
Method O
of O
relieving O
the O
public O
Burthens O
, O
than O
a O
new O
and O
heavy O
Imposition O
upon O
useful O
and O
industrious O
Subjects O
. O

Have O
great O
Things O
been O
promised O
for O
the O
Ease O
of O
the O
People O
of O
England B-Location
, O
and O
hath O
a O
Measure O
been O
fallen O
upon O
, O
that O
, O
by O
putting O
the O
Accomplishment O
of O
them O
at O
a O
Distance O
, O
and O
keeping O
Expectation O
alive O
, O
it O
may O
contribute O
to O
the O
Prolongation O
of O
a O
Power O
, O
which O
, O
in O
the O
Interim O
, O
will O
find O
sufficient O
Opportunities O
to O
gratify O
the O
Views O
of O
Ministerial O
Avarice O
or O
Ambition O
? O

If O
a O
Sum O
had O
been O
liquidated O
, O
and O
a O
precise O
Demand O
made O
, O
it O
might O
, O
perhaps O
, O
have O
been O
shewn O
, O
if O
proportioned O
to O
the O
Circumstances O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
to O
be O
of O
no O
real O
Consequence O
to O
the O
Nation B-Organization
; O
and O
, O
if O
above O
their O
Circumstances O
, O
that O
it O
would O
, O
with O
the O
Oppression O
of O
the O
Plantations B-Organization
, O
prove O
ruinous O
to O
the O
British O
Manufactures O
; O
but O
, O
whilst O
Matters O
are O
thus O
vague O
, O
and O
indeterminate O
, O
any O
Attempt O
to O
shew O
that O
the O
Stamp O
Duties O
will O
be O
inadequate O
to O
the O
promised O
Relief O
, O
distress O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
and O
consequently O
beggar O
the O
British O
Manufacturers O
, O
may O
be O
obviated O
by O
saying O
, O
that O
“ O
the O
Act O
is O
in O
the O
Nature O
of O
an O
Experiment O
; O
if O
inadequate O
, O
other O
Methods O
may O
be O
superadded O
; O
if O
inconvenient O
, O
it O
may O
be O
repealed O
, O
as O
soon O
as O
discovered O
; O
” O
and O
Hints O
may O
be O
thrown O
out O
at O
the O
same O
Time O
, O
to O
cherish O
the O
Hopes O
of O
the O
Nation B-Organization
, O
that O
there O
are O
the O
best O
Grounds O
to O
expect O
the O
Measure O
will O
be O
productive O
of O
all O
that O
can O
be O
desired O
or O
wished O
.4 O
The O
frugal O
Republicans O
of O
North-America B-Location
, O
( O
if O
the O
British O
Inhabitants O
there O
are O
to O
be O
distinguished O
by O
a O
Nick-Name O
, O
because O
it O
implies O
that O
They O
are O
Enemies O
to O
the O
Government B-Organization
of I-Organization
England I-Organization
, O
and O
ought O
therefore O
to O
be O
regarded O
with O
a O
jealous O
Eye O
) O
may O
be O
allowed O
, O
without O
derogating O
from O
the O
vast O
and O
prodigious O
knowledge O
of O
a O
Minister O
, O
to O
be O
acquainted O
with O
their O
own O
internal O
Circumstances O
better O
than O
a O
Stranger O
, O
who O
must O
depend O
upon O
Information O
; O
and O
that O
too O
, O
most O
frequently O
, O
of O
Men O
not O
the O
most O
eminent O
for O
their O
Candour O
, O
distinguished O
by O
their O
Sagacity O
, O
or O
respectable O
for O
their O
Integrity O
. O

Had O
Requisitions O
been O
made O
, O
and O
the O
Sum O
demanded O
been O
equitable O
, O
and O
proportioned O
to O
their O
Circumstances O
, O
They O
could O
have O
fallen O
upon O
Ways O
and O
Means O
less O
oppressive O
than O
the O
Stamp O
Duties O
. O

They O
have O
frequently O
taxed O
Themselves O
: O
They O
have O
tried O
various O
Methods O
of O
Taxation O
: O
They O
know O
, O
by O
Experience O
, O
the O
easiest O
and O
least O
expensive O
. O

— O
The O
Meaning O
, O
or O
Construction O
of O
their O
Levy-Acts O
is O
settled O
: O
They O
can O
be O
carried O
into O
Execution O
, O
not O
only O
at O
a O
small O
Expence O
, O
without O
exhausting O
a O
considerable O
Part O
of O
their O
Produce O
by O
the O
Multiplication O
of O
Officers O
, O
and O
their O
Support O
; O
but O
without O
heavy O
Pains O
and O
grievous O
Penalties O
, O
without O
Oppression O
of O
the O
innocent O
, O
giving O
Countenance O
to O
Vexation O
, O
and O
Encouragement O
to O
profligate O
Informers O
, O
without O
the O
Establishment O
of O
arbitrary O
and O
distant O
Courts B-Organization
of I-Organization
Admiralty I-Organization
.5 O
The O
national O
Debt O
is O
heavy O
, O
and O
it O
is O
a O
popular O
Scheme O
to O
draw O
from O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
a O
Contribution O
towards O
the O
Relief O
of O
the O
Mother-Country B-Organization
. O
— O
The O
Manner O
of O
effecting O
it O
is O
not O
carefully O
attended O
to O
, O
or O
nicely O
regarded O
by O
those O
who O
expect O
to O
receive O
the O
Benefit O
. O

— O
The O
End O
is O
so O
ardently O
desired O
, O
that O
, O
whether O
the O
Means O
might O
not O
be O
more O
moderate O
, O
is O
not O
scrupulously O
examined O
by O
Men O
, O
who O
think O
Themselves O
in O
no O
Danger O
of O
Injury O
or O
Oppression O
from O
their O
Severity O
. O

It O
is O
affirmed O
to O
those O
who O
cannot O
detect O
the O
Fallacy O
of O
the O
Assertion O
, O
that O
Millions O
have O
been O
expended O
solely O
in O
the O
Defence O
of O
America B-Location
. O

They O
believe O
it O
, O
and O
thence O
are O
easily O
persuaded O
that O
the O
Claim O
of O
a O
Contribution O
from O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
is O
just O
and O
equitable O
, O
and O
that O
any O
Measure O
necessary O
to O
secure O
it O
, O
is O
right O
and O
laudable O
. O

— O
It O
is O
represented O
, O
that O
unless O
the O
Colonies B-Location
are O
stripped O
of O
the O
Trial O
by O
Jury O
, O
and O
Courts O
of O
Admiralty O
are O
established O
, O
in O
which O
Judges O
from O
England B-Location
, O
Strangers O
, O
without O
Connection O
or O
Interest O
in O
America B-Location
, O
removeable O
at O
Pleasure O
, O
and O
supported O
by O
liberal O
Salaries O
, O
are O
to O
preside O
; O
unless O
Informers O
are O
encouraged O
and O
favoured O
, O
and O
the O
accused O
most O
rigorously O
dealt O
by O
, O
that O
the O
Tax O
will O
be O
eluded—and O
these O
Severities O
are O
excus O
’ O
d O
on O
Account O
of O
their O
supposed O
Necessity O
. O

The O
Colonies B-Organization
are O
described O
to O
be O
a O
numerous O
, O
flourishing O
, O
and O
opulent O
People O
: O
— O
It O
is O
alledged O
that O
They O
contribute O
to O
the O
national O
Expence O
, O
by O
Taxes O
there O
only O
the O
pitiful O
Sum O
of O
1900l O
. O
per O
Year O
, O
for O
the O
Collection O
of O
which O
, O
an O
Establishment O
of O
Officers O
, O
attended O
with O
the O
Expence O
of O
7600l O
. O
per O
Annum O
, O
is O
necessary O
. O

— O
Upon O
these O
Premisses O
, O
the O
Uneasiness O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
at O
being O
forced O
to O
bring O
more O
into O
the O
common O
Stock O
, O
appears O
to O
be O
unreasonable O
, O
if O
not O
rebellious O
; O
and O
They O
seem O
rather O
to O
deserve O
Reprehension O
and O
Correction O
, O
than O
Favour O
and O
Indulgence O
. O

The O
Successes O
of O
the O
War O
were O
obtained O
as O
well O
by O
the O
vigorous O
Efforts O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
as O
by O
the O
Exertion O
of O
Great-Britain B-Organization
—The O
Faith O
of O
Great-Britain B-Organization
hath O
been O
engaged O
in O
the O
most O
solemn O
Manner O
, O
to O
re-pay O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
the O
Monies O
levied O
by O
internal O
Taxations O
for O
the O
Support O
of O
the O
War O
. O

— O
Is O
it O
consistent O
with O
that O
Faith O
to O
tax O
Them O
towards O
sinking O
the O
Debt O
in O
Part O
incurred O
by O
that O
Re-payment O
? O

The O
immense O
Accession O
of O
Territory O
, O
and O
Value O
of O
the O
Acquisitions O
obtained O
by O
the O
Peace O
, O
is O
the O
Consequence O
of O
the O
Successes O
of O
the O
War—The O
Charge O
of O
the O
War O
is O
lessened O
by O
the O
Advantages O
resulting O
from O
the O
Peace—The O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
for O
a O
long O
Course O
of O
Time O
, O
have O
largely O
contributed O
to O
the O
public O
Revenue O
, O
and O
put O
Great-Britain B-Organization
to O
little O
or O
no O
Expence O
for O
their O
Protection O
. O

— O
If O
it O
were O
equitable O
to O
draw O
from O
Them O
a O
further O
Contribution O
, O
it O
does O
not O
therefore O
follow O
, O
that O
it O
is O
proper O
to O
force O
it O
from O
Them O
, O
by O
the O
harsh O
and O
rigorous O
Methods O
established O
by O
the O
Stamp-Act O
; O
an O
Act O
unequal O
and O
disproportioned O
to O
their O
Circumstances O
whom O
it O
affects O
; O
exempting O
Opulence O
, O
crushing O
Indigence O
; O
and O
tearing O
from O
a O
numerous O
, O
loyal O
, O
and O
useful O
People O
, O
the O
Privileges O
They O
had O
, O
in O
their O
Opinion O
, O
earned O
and O
merited O
, O
and O
justly O
held O
most O
dear O
. O

If O
They O
are O
really O
in O
Debt O
, O
the O
Payment O
of O
it O
hath O
not O
been O
refused O
, O
it O
hath O
not O
been O
demanded O
. O

— O
If O
one O
Subject O
, O
grown O
giddy O
with O
sudden O
Elevation O
, O
should O
, O
at O
any O
future O
Period O
, O
rashly O
declare O
, O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Location
should O
be O
taxed O
, O
at O
all O
Events O
, O
in O
the O
most O
rigorous O
Manner O
; O
and O
that O
Millions O
of O
industrious O
and O
useful O
Subjects O
should O
be O
grievously O
oppressed O
, O
rather O
than O
himself O
depart O
from O
his O
Character O
of O
Pertinacity O
and O
Wilfulness O
, O
check O
the O
Impulse O
of O
a O
tyrannical O
Disposition O
, O
or O
foregoe O
the O
Gratification O
of O
his O
Vanity O
, O
in O
a O
wanton O
Display O
of O
Power O
, O
Submission O
would O
be O
an O
admirable O
Virtue O
indeed O
, O
if O
not O
the O
Effect O
of O
Impotence O
. O

That O
the O
Contribution O
arising O
from O
the O
Stamp-Duties O
is O
disproportioned O
to O
their O
Circumstances O
from O
whom O
it O
is O
exacted O
, O
is O
manifest O
; O
for O
They O
will O
produce O
in O
each O
Colony B-Location
, O
a O
greater O
, O
or O
less O
Sum O
, O
not O
in O
Proportion O
to O
its O
Wealth O
, O
but O
to O
the O
Multiplicity O
of O
Juridical O
Forms O
, O
the O
Quantity O
of O
vacant O
Land O
, O
the O
Frequency O
of O
transferring O
landed O
Property O
, O
the O
Extent O
of O
Paper O
Negotiations O
, O
the O
Scarcity O
of O
Money O
, O
and O
the O
Number O
of O
Debtors O
. O

A O
larger O
Sum O
will O
be O
exacted O
from O
a O
Tobacco-Colony O
than O
from O
Jamaica B-Location
; O
and O
it O
will O
not O
only O
be O
higher O
in O
one O
of O
the O
poorest O
Colonies O
, O
and O
the O
least O
able O
to O
bear O
it O
, O
than O
in O
the O
richest O
; O
but O
the O
principal O
Part O
of O
the O
Revenue O
will O
be O
drawn O
from O
the O
poorest O
Individuals O
in O
the O
poorest O
Colonies O
, O
from O
Mortgagors O
, O
Obligors O
, O
and O
Defendants O
. O

If O
this O
be O
true O
, O
does O
the O
Act O
deserve O
the O
Encomium O
of O
being O
a O
Mode O
of O
Taxation O
the O
easiest O
, O
and O
the O
most O
equal O
, O
a O
Duty O
upon O
Property O
spread O
lightly O
over O
a O
great O
Variety O
of O
Subjects O
, O
and O
heavy O
upon O
none O
? O

The O
Commons B-Organization
of I-Organization
Great-Britain I-Organization
, O
moreover O
, O
in O
their O
Capacity O
of O
Representative O
, O
not O
only O
Give O
and O
Grant O
the O
Property O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
; O
but O
, O
in O
my O
Construction O
of O
the O
Stamp-Act O
, O
( O
however O
every O
Reader O
may O
examine O
and O
judge O
for O
himself O
, O
) O
Give O
and O
Grant O
also O
to O
certain O
Officers O
of O
the O
Crown B-Organization
, O
a O
Power O
to O
tax O
Them O
higher O
still O
; O
for O
these O
Officers O
will O
not O
, O
I O
presume O
, O
be O
called O
virtual O
Representatives O
too O
; O
and O
what O
They O
shall O
think O
fit O
to O
levy O
, O
by O
an O
ingenious O
Extent O
of O
the O
Fiction O
, O
will O
not O
be O
considered O
as O
levied O
with O
the O
Consent O
of O
the O
Colonies—The O
Instances O
, O
I O
believe O
, O
are O
rare O
, O
in O
which O
the O
Representatives B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
People I-Organization
of I-Organization
England I-Organization
have O
delegated O
to O
Officers B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Crown I-Organization
, O
the O
Power O
of O
taxing O
their O
Constituents O
, O
nor O
hath O
any O
Distinction O
yet O
been O
advanced O
to O
prove O
, O
that O
in O
their O
Capacity O
of O
virtual O
Representatives O
of O
the O
Colonies O
, O
the O
House B-Organization
of I-Organization
Commons I-Organization
not O
having O
the O
same O
Confidence O
reposed O
in O
Them O
, O
ought O
to O
proceed O
upon O
peculiar O
Rules O
. O

There O
was O
a O
Statute O
of O
Henry B-Person
VIII I-Person
, O
by O
which O
, O
I O
think O
, O
the O
King B-Organization
’ O
s O
Proclamations O
, O
with O
the O
Consent O
of O
the O
Privy B-Organization
Council I-Organization
, O
were O
to O
operate O
as O
Laws O
; O
and O
another O
Statute O
of O
Ric O
. O

II O
, O
that O
the O
Power O
of O
the O
Two B-Organization
Houses I-Organization
should O
be O
vested O
in O
Twelve O
Lords B-Organization
; O
but O
these O
Acts O
bear O
no O
Resemblance O
to O
the O
Stamp-Act O
. O

The O
Stamping O
Instruments O
are O
to O
be O
retained O
in O
England B-Location
. O

— O
Vellum O
, O
Parchment O
, O
and O
Paper O
, O
are O
to O
be O
sent O
to O
America B-Location
, O
ready O
stamped O
. O

— O
The O
first O
Commissioner B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Treasury I-Organization
, O
or O
the O
Commissioners B-Organization
, O
or O
any O
Three O
or O
more O
of O
Them O
, O
are O
, O
by O
the O
Act O
, O
impowered O
to O
set O
any O
Price O
upon O
the O
Vellum O
, O
Parchment O
and O
Paper O
, O
and O
the O
Payment O
of O
that O
Price O
is O
secured O
and O
enforced O
by O
the O
same O
Pains O
and O
Penalties O
that O
the O
Stamp-Duties O
are O
. O

If O
the O
Substitution O
of O
an O
arbitrary O
Civil O
Law O
Court O
, O
in O
the O
Place O
of O
the O
legal B-Organization
Judicatories I-Organization
, O
and O
that O
deserved O
Favourite O
, O
the O
Common-Law-Trial O
by O
Jury O
, O
would O
not O
justify O
the O
Assertion O
, O
that O
the O
Stamp-Act O
hath O
stripped O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
of O
the O
Guards O
and O
Securities O
provided O
by O
the O
Constitution O
against O
Oppression O
in O
the O
Execution O
of O
Laws O
, O
I O
would O
much O
less O
presume O
to O
say O
, O
the O
vesting O
in O
the O
Commissioners B-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Treasury I-Organization
a O
Power O
to O
tax O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
, O
will O
amply O
justify O
the O
Assertion O
, O
that O
the O
Stamp-Act O
hath O
not O
left O
Them O
even O
the O
Shadow O
of O
a O
Privilege O
. O

— O
It O
is O
indeed O
something O
difficult O
to O
imagine O
how O
the O
Order O
of O
Democracy O
, O
which O
is O
as O
much O
a O
Part O
of O
the O
Constitution O
, O
as O
Monarchy O
or O
Aristocracy O
, O
can O
exist O
when O
the O
People O
are O
excluded O
from O
a O
Share O
in O
the O
executing O
, O
and O
a O
Share O
in O
the O
making O
of O
Laws O
; O
but O
that O
is O
not O
the O
present O
Case O
; O
and O
, O
though O
I O
may O
not O
be O
able O
to O
answer O
a O
specious O
Objection O
, O
formed O
upon O
general O
Principles O
, O
I O
am O
not O
obliged O
to O
adopt O
it O
, O
’ O
till O
I O
am O
convinced O
of O
its O
Solidity O
. O

A O
little O
Examination O
will O
find O
how O
unfair O
and O
deceptive O
the O
Representation O
is O
, O
that O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
in I-Organization
North-America I-Organization
, O
“ O
Two O
Millions O
of O
British O
Subjects O
, O
an O
opulent O
, O
thriving O
and O
commercial O
People O
, O
contribute O
to O
the O
national O
Expence O
, O
no O
more O
than O
7 O
or O
800l O
. O
per O
Annum O
by O
Taxes O
raised O
there O
; O
” O
for O
tho O
’ O
it O
should O
be O
acknowledged O
( O
which O
I O
neither O
admit O
nor O
deny O
, O
because O
I O
don O
’ O
t O
know O
, O
nor O
have O
an O
Opportunity O
of O
coming O
at O
the O
Fact O
) O
that O
the O
Impositions O
upon O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
do O
not O
raise O
there O
, O
a O
greater O
Sum O
than O
hath O
been O
stated O
, O
it O
doth O
not O
follow O
that O
, O
“ O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
are O
indulged O
at O
the O
Expence O
of O
Great-Britain B-Organization
, O
and O
that O
the O
neediest O
British O
Cottager O
, O
who O
out O
of O
his O
scanty O
Pittance O
hardly O
earned O
, O
pays O
the O
high O
Duties O
of O
Customs O
and O
Excise O
in O
the O
Price O
of O
his O
Consumptions O
, O
has O
Reason O
to O
complain O
, O
” O
if O
immense O
Sums O
are O
raised O
upon O
the O
Inhabitants O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
elsewhere O
. O

By O
such O
Artifices O
and O
Sophistry O
, O
is O
Ignorance O
misled O
, O
Credulity O
deceived O
, O
and O
Prejudices O
excited O
. O

Thus O
Oppression O
gains O
the O
Credit O
of O
Equity O
, O
Cruelty O
passes O
for O
Moderation O
, O
and O
Tyranny O
for O
Justice O
, O
and O
the O
Man O
who O
deserves—Reproach O
, O
is O
celebrated O
by O
Adulation O
, O
and O
applauded O
by O
Delusion O
for O
his O
Wisdom O
and O
patriotic O
Virtues O
. O

The O
Truth O
is O
, O
that O
a O
vast O
Revenue O
arises O
to O
the O
British B-Organization
Nation I-Organization
from O
Taxes O
paid O
by O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
in I-Organization
GREAT-BRITAIN I-Organization
, O
and O
even O
the O
most O
ignorant O
British O
Cottager O
, O
not O
imposed O
upon O
by O
infamous O
Misrepresentation O
, O
must O
perceive O
, O
that O
it O
is O
of O
no O
Consequence O
to O
his O
Ease O
and O
Relief O
, O
whether O
the O
Duties O
raised O
upon O
America B-Location
are O
paid O
there O
, O
and O
thence O
afterwards O
remitted O
to O
Great-Britain B-Location
, O
or O
paid O
at O
first O
upon O
the O
produce O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Location
in I-Location
GreatBritain I-Location
. O

In O
the O
Article O
of O
Tobacco O
, O
for O
Instance O
, O
the O
Planter O
pays O
a O
Tax O
upon O
that O
Produce O
of O
his O
Land O
and O
Labour O
consumed O
in O
Great-Britain B-Location
, O
more O
than O
Six O
Times O
the O
clear O
Sum O
received O
by O
Him O
for O
it O
, O
besides O
the O
Expences O
of O
Freight O
, O
Commission O
and O
other O
Charges O
, O
and O
double O
Freight O
, O
Commission O
and O
Charges O
upon O
the O
Tobacco O
re-exported O
, O
by O
which O
the O
British O
Merchants O
, O
Mariners O
and O
other O
British O
Subjects O
, O
are O
supported—a O
Tax O
, O
at O
least O
, O
equal O
to O
what O
is O
paid O
by O
any O
Farmer O
of O
Great-Britain B-Location
, O
possessed O
of O
the O
same O
Degree O
of O
Property O
; O
and O
moreover O
the O
Planter O
must O
contribute O
to O
the O
Support O
of O
the O
expensive O
internal O
Government O
of O
the O
Colony O
, O
in O
which O
He O
resides O
.6 O
Is O
it O
objected O
, O
that O
the O
Duties O
charged O
upon O
Tobacco O
, O
fall O
ultimately O
upon O
the O
Consumers O
of O
this O
Commodity O
in O
the O
consequential O
Price O
set O
upon O
it O
? O

Be O
it O
so O
, O
and O
let O
the O
Principle O
be O
established O
that O
all O
Taxes O
upon O
a O
Commodity O
, O
are O
paid O
by O
the O
Consumers O
of O
it O
, O
and O
the O
Consequence O
of O
this O
Principle O
be O
fairly O
drawn O
, O
and O
equally O
applied O
. O

The O
British O
Consumers O
therefore O
, O
ultimately O
pay O
the O
high O
Duties O
laid O
upon O
Tobacco O
, O
in O
Proportion O
to O
the O
Quantity O
of O
that O
Commodity O
which O
They O
consume—The O
Colonies B-Organization
therefore O
, O
in O
Proportion O
to O
their O
Consumption O
of O
British O
Manufactures O
, O
pay O
also O
the O
high O
Duties O
of O
Customs O
and O
Excise O
, O
with O
which O
the O
Manufacturers O
are O
charged O
in O
the O
consequential O
Price O
set O
upon O
their O
Consumptions—In O
their O
Passage O
moreover O
, O
from O
the O
British O
Manufacturers O
to O
the O
American O
Importers O
, O
the O
Commodities O
go O
thro O
’ O
a O
great O
many O
Hands O
, O
by O
which O
their O
Costs O
are O
enhanced O
; O
the O
Factors O
, O
the O
Carriers O
, O
the O
Shop-keepers O
, O
the O
Merchants O
, O
the O
Brokers O
, O
the O
Porters O
, O
the O
Watermen O
, O
the O
Mariners O
, O
and O
Others O
, O
have O
their O
respective O
Profits O
, O
from O
which O
They O
derive O
their O
Subsistance O
, O
and O
the O
Support O
of O
their O
Families O
, O
and O
are O
enabled O
to O
pay O
the O
high O
Duties O
of O
Customs O
and O
Excise O
, O
in O
the O
Price O
of O
their O
Consumptions O
.7 O
The O
Policy O
of O
the O
late O
Regulations O
of O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
is O
of O
the O
same O
Character O
with O
their O
Justice O
, O
and O
Lenity O
. O

The O
Produce O
of O
their O
Lands O
, O
the O
Earnings O
of O
their O
Industry O
, O
and O
the O
Gains O
of O
their O
Commerce O
Center O
in O
Great-Britain B-Location
, O
support O
the O
Artificers O
, O
the O
Manufactories O
, O
and O
Navigation O
of O
the O
Nation B-Organization
, O
and O
with O
Them O
the O
British O
Land-holders O
too O
. O

Great-Britain B-Organization
had O
ALL O
before O
, O
and O
therefore O
can O
have O
no O
more O
from O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
; O
but O
the O
Minister B-Person
, O
in O
the O
pursuit O
of O
a O
“ O
well-digested O
, O
consistent O
, O
wise O
and O
salutary O
Plan O
of O
Colonization O
and O
Government O
, O
a O
Plan O
founded O
upon O
the O
Principles O
of O
Policy O
, O
Commerce O
and O
Finance O
, O
” O
chuses O
to O
demolish O
at O
one O
Blow O
, O
all O
their O
Privileges O
as O
they O
have O
understood O
Them O
, O
that O
he O
may O
raise O
in O
America B-Location
, O
a O
Part O
of O
what O
was O
before O
paid O
in O
Great-Britain B-Location
. O

But O
if O
the O
Execution O
of O
it O
, O
instead O
of O
improving O
the O
Advantages O
already O
possessed O
, O
confirming O
the O
Blessings O
already O
enjoyed O
, O
and O
promoting O
the O
Public O
Welfare O
, O
should O
happen O
to O
distress O
the O
Trade O
, O
reduce O
the O
Navigation O
, O
impoverish O
the O
Manufacturers O
, O
and O
diminish O
the O
Value O
of O
the O
Lands O
in O
Great-Britain B-Location
; O
should O
it O
drive O
the O
British O
Mechanics O
and O
Manufacturers O
to O
America B-Location
, O
by O
depriving O
Them O
of O
their O
best O
Customers O
at O
Home O
, O
and O
force O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
upon O
Manufactures O
, O
they O
are O
disabled O
from O
purchasing O
, O
other O
Topics O
of O
Eulogy O
must O
be O
discovered O
by O
his O
ingenious O
Encomiasts O
, O
than O
his O
Wisdom O
or O
his O
political O
Atchievements O
. O

Upon O
such O
an O
Event O
, O
an O
American O
will O
have O
very O
little O
Reason O
to O
exclaim O
O O
! O

me O
infelicem O
, O
qui O
nunc O
demum O
intelligo O
Ut O
illa O
mihi O
profuerint O
quæ O
despexeram O
, O
Et O
illa O
, O
quæ O
laudaram O
, O
quantum O
Luctus O
habuerint O
! O

The O
Right O
of O
Exemption O
from O
all O
Taxes O
without O
their O
Consent O
, O
the O
Colonies B-Organization
claim O
as O
British O
Subjects O
. O

They O
derive O
this O
Right O
from O
the O
Common O
Law O
, O
which O
their O
Charters O
have O
declared O
and O
confirmed O
, O
and O
They O
conceive O
that O
when O
stripped O
of O
this O
Right O
, O
whether O
by O
Prerogative O
or O
by O
any O
other O
Power O
, O
they O
are O
at O
the O
same O
Time O
deprived O
of O
every O
Privilege O
distinguishing O
Free-Men O
from O
Slaves O
. O

On O
the O
other O
Hand O
, O
They O
acknowledge O
Themselves O
to O
be O
subordinate O
to O
the O
Mother B-Organization
Country I-Organization
, O
and O
that O
the O
Authority O
vested O
in O
the O
supreme B-Organization
Council I-Organization
of I-Organization
the I-Organization
Nation I-Organization
, O
may O
be O
justly O
exercised O
to O
support O
and O
preserve O
that O
Subordination O
. O

Great O
and O
just O
Encomiums O
have O
been O
bestow O
’ O
d O
upon O
the O
Constitution O
of O
England B-Organization
, O
and O
their O
Representative O
is O
deservedly O
the O
Favourite O
of O
the O
Inhabitants O
in O
Britain B-Location
. O

But O
it O
is O
not O
because O
the O
supreme B-Organization
Council I-Organization
is O
called O
Parliament B-Organization
, O
that O
They O
boast O
of O
their O
Constitution O
of O
Government O
; O
for O
there O
is O
no O
particular O
magical O
Influence O
from O
the O
Combination O
of O
the O
Letters O
which O
form O
the O
Word O
; O
it O
is O
because O
They O
have O
a O
Share O
in O
that O
Council B-Organization
, O
that O
They O
appoint O
the O
Members O
who O
constitute O
one O
Branch O
of O
it O
, O
whose O
Duty O
and O
Interest O
it O
is O
to O
consult O
their O
Benefit O
, O
and O
to O
assert O
their O
Rights O
, O
and O
who O
are O
vested O
with O
an O
Authority O
, O
to O
prevent O
any O
Measures O
taking O
Effect O
dangerous O
to O
their O
Liberties O
, O
or O
injurious O
to O
their O
Properties O
. O

But O
the O
Inhabitants O
in O
the O
Colonies B-Location
have O
no O
Share O
in O
this O
great O
Council B-Organization
. O

None O
of O
the O
Members O
of O
it O
are O
, O
or O
can O
be O
of O
their O
Appointment O
, O
or O
in O
any O
Respect O
dependant O
upon O
Them O
. O
